Nikhil: Right.
Nikhil: Right,
kostadis: there we go. Okay. We'll do a start to record so I have some record of what happened.
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: And it will hopefully re-detect our voices. I need to go to the bathroom, and then we will continue.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: Chicago used to the stream. So let's go from there
kostadis: Oh, right. Yeah. I don't have to do anymore. It's, it's already there.
kostadis: Ooh, I have something for you
kostadis: Here. I have an extra one of these. 2014. That's the 2014 rules, not the '
Nikhil: 25. Top of those three
kostadis: This is the one I was looking at with you. I have them both, actually. Are these different? Yes. So 2025 edition.
Nikhil: Oh.
kostadis: 5.55. Okay.
Nikhil: Okay. Who, who, who governs these things? You know, the versions, the 5.5.5?
kostadis: Uh, a company called Hasbro and subdivision Wizards of the Coast. So Hasbro was the one who created the Stranger Things game?
Nikhil: No
kostadis: I'm familiar with transpose to
Nikhil: bio- All depends. One second.
kostadis: Okay. No, it's only in
Nikhil: here.
kostadis: No, yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay
kostadis: I can't seem to find it right now, so let's just, let's just... But yes, topic. Yeah. History's in it. Yeah, 1970s. Gary Gygax and Dave Arneson created Dungeons & Dragons. If
Nikhil: you wanna have the more fun version of it, search online.
kostadis: Search online?
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: Okay.
Nikhil: And if you're really curious- Who
kostadis: created it?
Nikhil: Okay ... it's, it's a funny story.
kostadis: Okay. All right. Okay. It starts. All right. So yeah,
Nikhil: so those are
kostadis: the books. Enjoy.
Nikhil: Okay. I, I'll just take the latest one.
kostadis: Take both of them. I- they're, they're collecting dust and I think-
Nikhil: Oh, you, you're not reading these?
kostadis: I have them online, and- Great ... I have, like, copies of them, so. Sweet. Thank you. Like, you are actually freeing space in my house.
Nikhil: Okay. Happy friendship day. Uh- Happy friendship day. You
kostadis: know, yeah, yeah, no, I mean, I... If I, if, I will, I'll give you actually one more, 'cause like, I, the, the, they're occupying space in my garage, right?
Nikhil: Right.
kostadis: I want them to get
Nikhil: And here's the monster manual
kostadis: Mm-hmm. So if you ever, like, this way you could learn all about monsters. Oh. I, I wouldn't recommend reading it 'cause it's always fun to be surprised, but if you ever wanted to learn what goblins are really like, you could go read them.
Nikhil: Mm.
kostadis: Right? So
Nikhil: the, the, the monster ... Okay, the, the monster book manual is useful for the DM, right?
kostadis: Yes, but I, I said, like I said, you may wanna-
Nikhil: Oh, it, it helps the, uh, players-
kostadis: Players, it's- ... to know- It, it's, it, it's, the goal is that, you know, the players, players have fun, right? I mean, the, the whole point of this game is it gives you ima- it, it, it, the point is to en- to tweak your imagination to have ideas.
kostadis: Correct. Yes. Right? That, that is the intent of it, nothing else. Make sense?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah Mm-hmm. Okay. It's gonna be my break time reading books
kostadis: So, and by the way, if... Just so you know, I have given you access to my entire RPG library on D&D Beyond.
Nikhil: Okay, perfect.
kostadis: Yeah, you should, you should be able to access all of my books there.
kostadis: Go,
kostadis: go to rules
kostadis: book.
Nikhil: What are the books like?
kostadis: Um.
Nikhil: Resources
kostadis: for some different document?
Nikhil: No, no, go to library. Okay, cool. View all. View
kostadis: all.
Nikhil: Click on that one.
kostadis: Right. Okay, that's the other one. Only shared one. Oh, these?
Nikhil: Yeah. Oh.
kostadis: These, these are all the ones I've purchased This is shared with me, meaning anyone that's shared with me, you could read
Nikhil: Okay.
Nikhil: Okay. Okay.
kostadis: Um...
Nikhil: Well, I don't have the monster manual here.
kostadis: Yeah, I know. I'm just... I, like, I s- that's why I'm happy to give them to you. Like- Right,
Nikhil: right, right. Yeah. Yeah. Okay ...
kostadis: right? I, I, I have it in dig- I have it in 10 digital formats, and so I've decided that I prefer... Now that I've figured out how to use the digital formats in LMs-
Nikhil: Oh, okay
kostadis: like, certain manuals just don't inspire me. Like, I have a, I have fancy versions of those which are, like, with special covers and whatnot. That I'm keeping.
Nikhil: Mm.
kostadis: But just the fifth edition rules, I haven't opened one of those books in ages.
Nikhil: Have you been to Grill'd House in San Jose?
kostadis: No. We should go there.
Nikhil: Yeah. We should go there.
kostadis: Right, so, all right. So let's just remind you of what happened last time.
Nikhil: Mm-hmm. All right. We went into the crypts there-
kostadis: It's, um...
kostadis: It's not what I want.
Nikhil: Back.
kostadis: What do you got? Yeah. It's reading this. Yeah.
kostadis: Okay. It's
Nikhil: like- You have the-
kostadis: I'm-- I don't know. You know where. Cheers. Alex, let me look at
kostadis: I like this. Yeah,
kostadis: it's pretty good. Thanks
kostadis: Is there a way, like, you know, as we were playing before- Yes ... there were a lot of side quests or choices that I had to choose, right? Yes. You go this way apparently. Is it possible to like, you know, uh, list all of those like a decision tree or something so that I can go, you know, pick-
Nikhil: Oh, you want the set of open quests?
kostadis: Yeah, yeah.
Nikhil: Uh, yeah.
kostadis: Yeah. I mean, like now because this is a quest
Nikhil: that I chose, it's done.
kostadis: Well, no, it's, uh,
Nikhil: you want
kostadis: the list
Nikhil: of open
kostadis: quests?
Nikhil: Right. Yeah.
kostadis: Okay. It's actually pretty easy for me to
Nikhil: generate. I mean, I don't need it right now, but-
kostadis: No, no, no, no. This is really easy for me to generate.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: That is, that is actually something I can do very quickly
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Um, I can, I can remind you just like...
kostadis: No, I'm sorry
kostadis: Nice.
kostadis: Yes, I will, I will get that to you. Uh, we have-- But right now we, we-- Right now we are not quite at that point right now.
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: Well, there's a couple things we need to decide, right?
kostadis: Um,
kostadis: There we go. All right. So, uh, let me see.
kostadis: All right. All right. Okay. So, uh, blah, blah, blah. Let me just get one more thing up. Uh, I have my, my summaries, but what we would have it come
kostadis: All right, so you're standing outside of the prison, if I'm not mistaken, yes? Yep, yeah. All right. There's a couple of things that, um... There's a couple open, there's a couple of loose threads. Okay? One loose thread is the bugbears. The bugbear from the other room? Yes. Yeah. Yeah. And so, you know, if these guys have bosses, they might be, they might be somebody you wanna go deal with before it's too late
kostadis: The bugbears, I will show you where they are.
Nikhil: I don't think
kostadis: they are in this-
Nikhil: Uh, like scroll, scroll to the left.
kostadis: Yeah.
Nikhil: See there, the, the bugbears.
kostadis: Oh, yeah, yeah. Okay, okay, okay. Yeah. I didn't want... Yeah, okay.
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Are you saying like when if we leave them as they are, like they can, you know, bring backup? Or worse,
Nikhil: tell people- Tell people.
Nikhil: Right
Nikhil: Um, what's the other loose, loose
kostadis: thread? Um, okay, so that's one loose thread. Yeah. All right. Sorry. Let me just start off with, um...
kostadis: So there's escort the, um, uh, escort the den- escort the family, find-- talk to the family.
Nikhil: Correct.
kostadis: Yeah. They, they just, just freed them. They have no idea.
Nikhil: They need to be, you know, uh, brought, brought back outside.
kostadis: Right. You know, find out who they are. Um-
Nikhil: These are the groups.
kostadis: Um, there's also the Crevasse, like that creature of the Mauthe.
Nikhil: Right. Right. The, the creature.
kostadis: Right.
Nikhil: Can
kostadis: I not leave it like that? Um, uh.
kostadis: Okay, so what?
Nikhil: Can I not leave the creat-creatures like that and just go out?
kostadis: Yeah, you can. I'm just... I mean, yes, but who knows what treasures it has, right?
Nikhil: I don't want to pick. Ah, okay.
kostadis: All right, so, um, so yeah
kostadis: Okay. So your choices are, let's say your choice, you've all now leveled up to level three. Okay. So four bugbears should be a relatively straightforward thing for you guys to handle. The downside is you haven't taken a long rest. All right. Right. So you can either hope that the bugbears don't go anywhere, or you can go attack them now.
kostadis: Now, remember, you are dressed like Redbrands. Correct. They haven't actually seen you kill anybody.
Nikhil: Correct.
kostadis: So you could just bluff your way to a surprise attack.
Nikhil: Like-
kostadis: Right?
Nikhil: Like- I
kostadis: just wanna make sure you, you, you like...
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah, yeah. I was thinking like, you know,
kostadis: uh, rescuing the family outside, uh, there's a creature, there are bugbears.
kostadis: Like, if I'm, uh, you know, identified by any one of those two, like, you know, it's, it's, they're gonna kill this family and us, right? So
Nikhil: you're thinking free the family first?
kostadis: So if I try to free the family, this is the, this could be a possible outcome, right? You know, bugbears could attack us when... Well, so, so, so, so, um, oh, hold on.
kostadis: Like, uh, when I am trying to fight the bugbears, at that time the family is not safe. So right now I can go to fight the bugbears, kill them, then bring the family, try, try to bring the family outside. Or you can bring them out. What if I encounter the bugbears when I'm trying to
Nikhil: bring them
kostadis: out? As the first eight.
Nikhil: Yeah. You know, the family will be in danger.
kostadis: Right.
Nikhil: Right. So-
kostadis: So you're gonna
Nikhil: Tell them wait a second?
kostadis: Why did we just take it like that without uh-
Nikhil: They're, they're, they're kind of... Okay. Well, first of all, they probably wanna talk to you, right?
kostadis: Correct. Yes, yes. First I'm gonna know what was happening
Nikhil: Uh,
Nikhil: right
kostadis: All right. So, um, you appro-- so you, you wanna, you, you first are up to the, the, uh, Dendrars, right? Right. Yeah. All right. So let's just...
Nikhil: And
kostadis: we should now be able to see their names. Let me guess. Like, they were once the owner of this manor, and then they were kinda... I'm just guessing.
Nikhil: No, it's not... It's u- usually not a bad guess.
kostadis: Yeah.
Nikhil: Um, but this time it would be the wrong guess.
kostadis: Is it Dendrar or Dendrar? Dendrar
kostadis: So Thel's got a little more fire in him. All right. Mirna Dendrar-- So it's Mirna Dendrar and her teenage children, thirteen-year-old Nars and eighteen-year-old Nilsa. Mm-hmm. All in good kids. Well, yes. If he goes, uh, well, she, she, she's very excited to see you. What do you tell her?
Nikhil: Yeah, we have cleared almost everyone. Like, I hope, uh, Redbrands.
kostadis: You don't have to, like, role play. You
Nikhil: can tell me what you're saying, what you want to say. You don't have to actually act if you don't want to.
kostadis: No, no, no. I, I'm even really bad at, like... You know, I'm just trying to put myself in that situation. Like, if I saved someone, like, I don't know, what do I say? But yeah, I hope you guys are safe.
kostadis: Uh, and, uh, d- do you need... Y- you look very starved. Like, I think first you guys need some food. Like, uh, food and water.
Nikhil: All right. Well, they're very... So they're very happy to get that. That's very thoughtful of you. Um, so, um, they, they
kostadis: start eating the food. Mirna then explains that a couple of days ago, the Redbrands murdered her husband.
kostadis: "My husband, Thel. And they were gonna kill us, too, but I promised them that we had wealthy reve- well, relatives in Neverwinter who would pay a substantial sum for us and the children's safety.
Nikhil: The Redbrands kept us safe, kept us here while they developed a plan."
kostadis: Wait, w- w- okay. W- were they trying to- Ransom us No. Were they being sold as slaves by the Redbrands? She pauses.
Nikhil: No, they, their original plan was to kill us all What would they get out of it? I don't know. No?
kostadis: No. They roll an insight check.
Nikhil: Yeah,
kostadis: insight
Nikhil: check. D20. Let's roll a D20
kostadis: First roll an insight check. Roll a D20 and then I'll tell you, then I'll tell you if you have to bother checking your daily rolls. Uh.
Nikhil: Um, plus four. Zero.
kostadis: Plus zero. Okay, you don't succeed, but, uh, but there's, uh... Okay. Sister Maela goes, knocks, taps you. She goes, "Uh, boss, remember that guy we gave up for food?"
Nikhil: Thank you.
Nikhil: Okay. Yeah. Yeah. I do.
kostadis: Yes. Well, she looks at the three people there-
Nikhil: No, no. Okay. I mean, I
kostadis: can And she goes, "I, I, I'm guessing..." Uh, I
Nikhil: don't know.
kostadis: What?
Nikhil: Fair enough, but
kostadis: I was just trying to get more insight, like if they have any, you know, prominent role, you know, were the Redbrands threatened by this family? Um... It's quite possible.
Nikhil: Well, she goes... She, w-
kostadis: what'd you say?
Nikhil: No, you know, these people, uh, could have something of value to the Redbrands.
kostadis: Ah, so she, so, so she explains. Oh, so you're saying like, uh, so the, the, the Red- What she told the Redbrands. She goes, "Oh, oh, it's really simple. The Redbrands were planning to kill us. I mean, they, they took Thel. He hasn't come back, and I think something terrible's happened to him."
Nikhil: Yeah. Okay, okay. Maybe the creature ate, ate him.
kostadis: Yes. Do you tell her that or?
Nikhil: No, I don't tell her that.
kostadis: Okay.
Nikhil: No. I don't want to. I
kostadis: just, I just-
Nikhil: I, I hope your husband is safe somewhere. You know, maybe he'll be back, or...
kostadis: Yes. You, you, you tell her whatever she needs to hear. Yes.
Nikhil: Like the movies.
kostadis: What?
kostadis: Right, right. And then she goes, um, she goes... Well, she goes, "My husband was murdered, so, you know..." But you don't tell her, "But I don't know where his body is." Yeah, yeah. Do you know where his body is? No. Roll a deception.
Nikhil: I'm trying that. Oh, that's a bad deception. Um,
Nikhil: I think those dice are weighted.
kostadis: Yeah, dude, yes, they all say. Uh, roll, uh, do you want me to get you more dice so that you can- No, no, I, I can... I have more dice. We- You don't understand. I have more dice.
Nikhil: Okay, so let's try with another one. No, no, but not the box
kostadis: Yeah. You got an entire box to the office now.
Nikhil: Yeah, I know. I can't find the other one somewhere. Um...
kostadis: Do you, do you notice those? Like, it's this heavier.
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah. It is heavier. Yeah, they're different. This one's more balanced. Dude, it doesn't matter. Like, just,
kostadis: like, the- Okay. Yeah
kostadis: Should I roll again? Perception? Yes.
Nikhil: I, okay. Um, she goes, "You know where, you know where Thel is?"
Nikhil: She, she, she, she knows you're lying
kostadis: Oh, okay. Because the reception was bad?
Nikhil: Yes
kostadis: No, uh, buh, buh, buh, I, I actually don't know. I was just, uh ... I don't know the truth, so I was just saying
Nikhil: You, so you're, you're bluffing
kostadis: Yeah. Like, I mean, like-
Nikhil: You, you're cau- you've been caught lying right now
kostadis: Yeah.
Nikhil: About her husband's body.
Nikhil: I mean, this is the time to be honest
kostadis: Uh, okay, fine. Uh- Um, you're not.
Nikhil: It's up to you
kostadis: No, as, as I'm not being honest, I'm just trying to think how I can cover it up. Well- Do
Nikhil: you wanna be nice about it?
kostadis: Yeah. Yeah.
Nikhil: You, you could turn to Sister Maela and say, and tell, tell her to tell him. She's a cleric. Maybe she knows how to do it better.
Nikhil: Right?
kostadis: Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Okay. That's a good choice. Yeah. I'll, I'll tell Maela. I'll delegate this to Maela. Maela. Yes. Um-
Nikhil: All right, let's see what Maela does
Nikhil: Maela does a half-decent job.
kostadis: She avoids saying probably being, being torn to shreds and eaten alive by a monster
Nikhil: Thank you, Maela. That was wonderful.
kostadis: She, she, she ba- she makes it slightly better than that
Nikhil: Better than that, okay. And is, is, uh, the mother satisfied with that?
kostadis: Yes, the mother is ... Satisfied is the worst possible word you could describe it. So, I mean, she, is she relieved?
kostadis: Uh, all right. She, she, she, she thanks you for being honest. Um, and then in gratitude she says, um, I... She goes, "My, I was lying about the, I was lying about the folks in Neverwinter." Okay. Um, "The, I was just trying to buy time and the Redbrands hadn't figured it out yet. I was hoping somebody would come s- rescue me, so thank you so much for rescuing me."
kostadis: But she does say, um, "I know where I have valuable heirloom is hidden."
Nikhil: Valuable? Heirloom.
kostadis: Heirloom.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: Um, "When I was a young girl, me and my family fled from the town of Thundertree after the Owlbear overran the place. My family had an urban alchemy shop. Inside which is an emerald necklace in a case hidden behind a section of storage shelves.
kostadis: I never dared to return it, return to retrieve it. The shop is in the southeast part of Thundertree. If you ever wanna go there, I, you guys can go claim it and make it yours."
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: So, like,
Nikhil: claiming the shop?
kostadis: No, no, claiming the necklace, dude.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: Um, um, Pip goes, "The necklace, buddy."
Nikhil: I, uh-
kostadis: Hold on, let me just show you where But I don't have the bow, right? Uh, to get that. Yes. So here, I'm just gonna put you on this- The world map. Yeah, so I'm gonna switch you to the world map and put
kostadis: Uh, very much hope to go ahead.
kostadis: Right. Let me just put one. Can you see that you should see something? Let me see. A notary. Yes. That's good. Here in our window. Yes.
kostadis: Treasure
kostadis: According to Una. Right? Mm-hmm. Can you see that? Yes, I think I do. All right, good. Go back home.
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Which means to get there, I have to go back to almost another winter.
Nikhil: Yeah, I mean, it's, it's a bit of a ways. But, I mean-
kostadis: Yeah. Well, well, uh, yeah, thank you, Veyra. Uh, if, if, uh, there's, uh... I mean, if we ever go on that way, we will, uh, come
Nikhil: back.
Nikhil: Um,
kostadis: Pip
Nikhil: goes, "If?" If, I mean, if-
kostadis: Dude, emerald
Nikhil: necklace ...
kostadis: once we are done with all of the cleaning up the sand dune and finding, uh,
Nikhil: you know- Pip,
kostadis: Pip, Pip takes your assets, boss. You know what we do with treasure?
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: See that crappy armor
Nikhil: I have?
kostadis: Dude, we only have like tons of gold coins that could be tons of
Nikhil: Do, do, do I have the best armor?
Nikhil: No, you can get one with one of the, with, with all the money
kostadis: we have. He goes, "No, I can't. Do you know how much a full plate costs?"
Nikhil: Not really.
kostadis: Yeah, it costs several thousand gold pieces. We do not have several thousand gold pieces.
kostadis: He's like, "Boss, I, I don't, I don't, I don't... I mean, I'm, I'm all for heroism, doing a good thing, and periodically serving, uh, evil bandits to, uh, unspeakable horrors and monsters, but I do wanna get better armor."
Nikhil: I agree, but it's, it's,
kostadis: we... it's very far away.
Nikhil: Yeah, I just, just wanna make sure we, we, we have it on the radar.
kostadis: We do have it on the radar. All
Nikhil: right. So as, as long as... He goes, "As long as it's on the radar."
kostadis: Yes. We will go get something.
Nikhil: Is that someday in the future or someday in, like, never?
kostadis: Someday in the future.
Nikhil: Okay. Jus- just checking. Yes. Just checking.
kostadis: I mean, he goes, he goes, "I don't know, man. Like, you speak very...
kostadis: Your, your, your, your common is a little bit different than mine." Common. Uh, uh, what's her name? Uh, Sister Maela raises an eyebrow
kostadis: Um, and you get the distinct impression that Pip's English common is, is, does, is kind of sounds funny to her too. Um, it's kind of like everybody's like... All right, so what was I looking at? All right. Okay, so you, you found out about, uh, a new, a new possible quest
kostadis: Okay, let's see. I think I have something
Nikhil: for you. No, no, see me? Are they still eating?
kostadis: What? Uh, no, they're, they're done eating.
Nikhil: They're done eating. Yes?
Nikhil: So what do you want? She goes, um So,
kostadis: so, uh, let us take you back, uh, to the safe place in Phandalin. W- would you be okay with that? Uh,
Nikhil: I think she goes, "I would be delighted with that."
kostadis: Okay. Cool. Um-
Nikhil: So we're going now?
kostadis: Yes. Uh, at least, uh, like, yeah, whatever
Nikhil: She then pauses
kostadis: and says, "Do you ha- Would..." So, um, she says, "Well..."
kostadis: She pauses and says, "Well, you know, you, you brought me closure that I at least know where Thel is." Mm-hmm. "Although if you could get his body, I would be much obliged." Mm-hmm.
Nikhil: I can try for that
kostadis: All right. She just, she just leaves it at that. But okay.
kostadis: Uh.
kostadis: So, uh, where would you like to go next?
Nikhil: So, uh-
kostadis: Do you wanna take her out or do you wanna, like, continue to go solve the bugbear problem?
Nikhil: Uh, I wanna take her out. Okay.
kostadis: Like, okay, so, so, uh, one thing. Yeah. We entered the manor from the forest through the back door, like- Yes ... the secret door.
Nikhil: Oh, she's saying do you...
Nikhil: Is there another way in?
kostadis: No, there's gotta be a front door, right?
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: Yeah. So I'll let them out from the front door and then go to- All right.
Nikhil: Well, so, okay, so we'll... Where do you think the front door is? Uh, that's what I can't see through the map.
kostadis: Well, so, um-
Nikhil: Is, is this all, like, under the-
kostadis: Manor, manor. So, you know, um-
Nikhil: Okay
Nikhil: so- We still haven't explored the manor
kostadis: Well, the manor was, you knew was empty. It was just a ruin.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: So, uh, just so you know, there's a couple of doors that you saw that you haven't explored. Uh, let me just show you. One map. It's here. Oh, you can't see. All right. There we go. No, I'm just trying to see if you can see.
kostadis: All right. So I'm gonna draw this here so you can see it. Okay You see there? There's one door you haven't explored
Nikhil: Good. Okay
kostadis: Which is going up, so that is possibly the, the exit
Nikhil: Okay
kostadis: Um, those are the, those are the only two things. And the o- every other door you've explored
Nikhil: Okay. This is the only one.
Nikhil: Where is the other one? The second one that I found
kostadis: No, there is no one. That's what I realized
Nikhil: That's the only one. Okay
kostadis: So if I was gonna guess, that would ... If you were gonna guess, that's
Nikhil: where you would guess. Wanna go check it out?
kostadis: Yeah
Nikhil: All right.
kostadis: You're gonna- O- okay. I'm thinking like, do I take the family with me or, you know, leave them here and come
Nikhil: back?
Nikhil: They don't wanna be left here
kostadis: Okay, cool. Yeah. All right. Um, two in the front, two in the back, and all,
Nikhil: you know, three family members in the middle-
kostadis: All right ...
Nikhil: escorting
kostadis: All right. So you go over to here, you open the door, and you end up
kostadis: Yeah, you can go ahead. Oh, okay. From the onset? Yep. There you are. You're in panel.
Nikhil: Yeah. Thanks.
kostadis: All right?
Nikhil: Yeah. Not everybody's... So, nothing
kostadis: All right. More a castle than a house, Tresendar Manor stands at the east edge of town on a low hillside among woods and thickets. The ancient manor has long been abandoned. Its cellars have been converted into a Redbrand stronghold, or conver- converted into a Redbrand stronghold. All right, you gonna go back down to deal with the bugbears?
Nikhil: Yes. Yeah.
kostadis: All right. Okay.
kostadis: All right. So which way do you-- There, you, you, there's this door you haven't explored over here. Oh, wait, I didn't shift. Shift that. I didn't shift from there.
kostadis: Right. Can you see this? You should be able to see this point over here when I'm clicking
Nikhil: Oh, yeah. Okay. There's a door over there?
kostadis: Yeah, there's a door over there. Okay. Yeah, cool. You go that way? Yep.
Nikhil: All right.
kostadis: I think it's taking me to the Nordic creatures again Do you want to keep going? No. Uh, no, that's taking me to the Nordic creatures, so... Okay, no,
kostadis: no, I don't wanna keep going into that. You don't wanna- I wanna deal with the bugbears first
Nikhil: You wanna go to the bugbears? You wanna go through the north, I presume, right? Yeah.
kostadis: Yeah. There's no creature right now. I know it's super into the-
Nikhil: All right. So you're gonna go this way.
kostadis: This way. The same way that we came, uh, came into the...
kostadis: Right?
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Uh, back into Glasstaff's Workshop and then, uh-
Nikhil: Yep.
kostadis: Yeah. So you're gonna go through Glasstaff's Workshop Um, meanwhile, the creature is munching away.
Nikhil: Table? Wonderful.
kostadis: Well, remember all the people you killed in the, uh, the, the, this room over here? The gambling room with the bu- ruffians?
kostadis: There were a bunch of ruffians here, remember? Here. I'm about to show you the, uh ... You see them now? No. You can see. Oh, yeah. Hold on. I know the problem. I put it in the wrong layer
kostadis: Yeah, I should say. Remember you killed him?
Nikhil: Yes, yes, I don't know this
kostadis: That's what she, that, what, you're absolutely sure right now
Nikhil: But the bodies were here and the creature was here.
kostadis: Yes. Remember when you came over here, the creature went to get the bodies over there.
Nikhil: So there's no creature here right now?
kostadis: Well, I mean, you're hearing munching sounds.
Nikhil: Okay. No, the creature was like-
kostadis: The creature was in the crevasse.
Nikhil: Correct.
kostadis: All right, let's just call this, uh... We're, let's just, uh, keep to make it. This is the crevasse, right? Mm-hmm
kostadis: Wait, this is the crevasse area. Okay? Yeah. You can see it, right?
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: So, um, and this is where Glasstaff escaped from. Correct. Yes. I'm gonna get rid of, I'm gonna get rid of those things that are there while we complete this. Right?
kostadis: Okay. So what had happened was that the creature, after you guys killed everything over here- Mm-hmm
kostadis: I don't remember exactly what happened, but I think he, I think what happened was he heard all the dead bo- He heard all the things, and he decided to go get himself some food.
Nikhil: He smelled some blood.
kostadis: Yes.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: Right? He smelled some blood, you know, food, food to be eaten.
Nikhil: Okay. So he's normal. Okay, cool. Yeah, yeah.
Nikhil: All right. Then, then we'll, um, go into the crevasse directly from the, uh, what is that, apothecary room?
kostadis: The apothecary?
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: All right, so you're gonna go in there. All right. Okay. So, um, I'm going to assume you're gonna try not to be loud and obnoxious.
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: Okay. So we'll use, uh... Does Zenvon want to, like, sneak in by himself, or, um-
Nikhil: Yes, yeah.
Nikhil: Yeah, I mean, sneak. Uh, ev- everyone has to sneak through.
kostadis: Well, do, would you... So the question is, so ev- Pip looks at you, "So are we going all together, boss, or are you gonna go explore it on your own?"
kostadis: Um, Veyra goes, "All probabilities tell me that the connections that you would make on your own could probably result in your untimely demise." Okay, that sounds like- Well, why are we even given the choice? Like, everybody should work together. Um, Sister Maela goes, "I don't know about you guys, but I've been told that the easiest way for the party to die is for it to split up."
Nikhil: Split up. Yeah, makes sense.
kostadis: It goes, "Never split up the party."
Nikhil: Right. So that's all tiptoe and-
kostadis: Yeah. All right, you're all gonna tiptoe? All right, roll your stealth
kostadis: All right. Pip rolled a natural 20, so as long as you didn't... Oh, God, you blew your 7.
Nikhil: No, I have a plus 7.
kostadis: Oh, you have a plus 7?
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: All right.
Nikhil: 40.
kostadis: Okay.
kostadis: All right.
kostadis: The creature doesn't notice you. Okay.
Nikhil: No, that's not what I wanted
kostadis: All right. All right
kostadis: Right. So, um, we were in, um...
kostadis: All right. Technology's not taking me through right now.
kostadis: Okay. So, uh, what do we have here? United Redbrand try it
kostadis: out. Okay
kostadis: A cold breeze sighs softly in this natural carra- cavern, carrying the faint sign of decaying fesh- flesh. A faint crevasse with sloped walls divides the cavern and is flanked by rough, two rough stone columns that support the 20-foot high ceiling. Two arched wooden bridges span, uh, the caverns.
Nikhil: Mm-hmm
Nikhil: Crevasse, is it like a, is this
kostadis: like a small valley? Uh, yeah. Crevasse is a- Okay. Yeah Uh, it- the, the steep side fissure is 5 to 10 feet wide and 20 feet deep. Mm-hmm. You wanna go down? I think we're... Why would I want to go down? No No. I need to go to the bug bears. Okay. Steal
Nikhil: Daz treasure while it's not here.
kostadis: Oh, it's very good treasure. Do you think that- Pip, Pip, Pip, Pip, Pip goes, Pip goes, "You aren't really good
Nikhil: at this thieving thing, were you?"
kostadis: Well, um, having to... You know, I think I lost touch a bit.
kostadis: Ever since this adventure began, I lost my practice. You're, you're out of practice. Yeah. Okay.
Nikhil: I just keep a monster. That's where I store my treasure
Nikhil: I go down, check
kostadis: It's what, like five feet wide and 20 feet deep?
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: And what if the monster comes to the portal when you come back up? That's what you got backup for.
kostadis: Oh, wait, we have many bosses. God, I really want that monster dead. But see, don't... Secrets about him that I want Eddie to know.
kostadis: Is this where you push
Nikhil: him in? Yes, he is. Okay. You, it's your call
kostadis: 'Cause we never know when the monster is gonna come back
Nikhil: Note.
kostadis: Okay. That's, that's, that's dangerous All right. Um, um, okay. Our roll is stealth check.
kostadis: Bad stealth. What? Bad stealth. Okay, let's see what his- No, it's two plus seven, nine. Mm-hmm. And we-
kostadis: The creature, you hear the creature make a noise.
kostadis: Wow. Um,
Nikhil: let's see. What's the
kostadis: big one? Are you planning to play the song? Yes. Okay.
kostadis: That's a Windows sound No, that's the, that's the Chrome OS sound. Yeah
Nikhil: That chilly creepy
kostadis: Yes. So you, you hear that creepy sound.
Nikhil: Yeah. Uh.
kostadis: You already have that illusion. You might wanna try- this would be a good time for you to try that illusion.
Nikhil: Oh, one of the spells?
kostadis: Yeah.
Nikhil: Minor illusion? Yeah. Yes. So you could use the minor illusion to make it seem as if there's something coming else from somewhere else.
kostadis: Create a phenomenon in the
kostadis: middle of it
kostadis: And the sound can come from somewhere else? Yes. Okay. Yes. That's a good idea Maybe I want, uh, the sound to
Nikhil: come from the wizard room
kostadis: Um, wizard room? Do you have to have line of sight?
Nikhil: Oh, I can do it only where I have sight?
kostadis: Yeah, you could do it, like, over there up to room number seven if you wanted. Or you could do it down there.
Nikhil: Here?
kostadis: Yes Or you could do it, I, I, you could also do it up in the, uh, wizard laboratory
Nikhil: But that has the, uh, access... No, I'm, I'm trying to, uh, you know, take the creature-
kostadis: I mean, like- ...
Nikhil: out of this, you know, anywhere it is connected
kostadis: Right, so the workshop, for example
Nikhil: Workshop. Okay. Yeah, yeah. But I don't have a line of sight to workshop as well.
kostadis: Uh, I'm gonna say you do
Nikhil: Okay. Okay. Then, then, uh, make a sound from the workshop, like the Glasstaff is working or something Glasstaff?
kostadis: Yeah Is the sound you're making?
Nikhil: Yeah. Uh, that's the creature's boss, right? So- Okay,
kostadis: okay, okay. The creature suddenly stops. The creature suddenly becomes silent.
Nikhil: Yeah
kostadis: All right. Okay. Um, Maela's very impressed. Are you gonna keep this? That's good stuff. Very impressed. All right.
kostadis: All right, you descended to the fissure and you find a chest
kostadis: You wanna open the chest? Yes,
Nikhil: yes, of course.
kostadis: This is where you could use your ... You have mage hand, right? As an ar- artificer, I think you have mage hand. I do have mage hand,
Nikhil: but go ahead.
kostadis: All right, so you don't have to open the chest here. You can use your mage hand to open the chest.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: All right. Uh, the chest opens, and it contains 160 silver pieces, t- 120 gold pieces, five malachite gems worth 12 gold pieces each, a potion of viewing, a potion of climbing, and a potion of growth.
kostadis: The chest also contains a plus one long sword.
Nikhil: I'll take it.
kostadis: What? You, you, you take it, but you probably wanna give that to Pip because he's your biggest fighter.
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah.
kostadis: All right. Okay. Um, let's just add this to your treasure.
Nikhil: Please tell me this, like, um-
kostadis: Yes ... I could have opened the chest, the treasure chest with my guy.
Nikhil: Yes
kostadis: Instead of using the mage hand.
kostadis: And it could just be the same.
Nikhil: No, because there was a trap
kostadis: Okay. That's what I mean, like you-
Nikhil: Poison
kostadis: Oh, okay ...
Nikhil: all sorts of traps
kostadis: So the rule of thumb is, like, you don't use your actual hand to open anything?
Nikhil: Yes
kostadis: In this game
Nikhil: Yes. Minics. There's all sorts of monsters whose only
kostadis: purpose in life is to teach you don't touch.
kostadis: That's true. All right? Um, yeah. So, like, there's a whole bunch of, uh, things that exist in this module which I- could basically be boiled down to don't touch. Make sense?
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: All right. So, um, let me just, uh-
kostadis: No, I'll just stop it.
kostadis: Um, let's see. I'm just trying to find that. Okay, so what do we have? Push, uh... So let me just-- I'm gonna add your treasure here, so it's, um... So let me see this. Uh, hundred and...
Nikhil: One sixty and one twenty.
kostadis: All right. One sixty silver pieces.
Nikhil: No, one sixty gold, one twenty. Oh,
kostadis: no, one sixty silver. Silver? One sixty silver, one twenty gold
kostadis: And then portion of, uh, five times twenty, twelve is sixty. Sixty gold pieces for the gems. And then a portion of inventory. Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Oh, that's what you mean. A cushion. So we need to add a cushion of yarn. Cushion of... So let's
kostadis: see. Cushion of... Building, climbing, and growth.
kostadis: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: All right. Okay. Um, Pip is very pleased. All right. Uh, you now have all, you now have all this ... By the way, if you go to your cr- he goes, "Excellent. All right, now let's go deal with these guys." All right. You head down over here. All right. Okay, one more, uh, stealth check
Nikhil: Okay, I'm gonna try with a different die. Okay? Yeah. Uh, let me go
kostadis: back. Yes. Okay. So you did, um- I had seven. No, that's, that was, um... Okay, so you managed to, you, you... Pi- uh, what's his name? Nars and, uh, what's her name, did 18 and 13, and so with your, with Pip, uh, we're gonna use that as Pip's die roll.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: You man- you managed to allow stealthily out the door.
kostadis: All right.
Nikhil: Um, um,
kostadis: can you make a nature check? Yeah. To, to, to do what? To open the door? Yeah. I mean, can, can I, uh... First wanna hear, like- You wanna hear what's going on, right? Yes. So insight check?
Nikhil: Yes, roll an insight check
Nikhil: All right. Um, does somebody w- uh,
kostadis: Maela, Sister Maela kind of pushes you aside and tries to join her thoughts with me. Uh, she hears something. All right. Uh, she hears several gruff voices issuing commands in the goblin tongue. Okay. Um ... Okay.
kostadis: Wanna get in? So what you're, the ins- insight you have is that somebody is giving orders to a goblin.
Nikhil: Yes, I will use my mage hand to open the door. All
kostadis: right.
Nikhil: And, uh... Okay, yeah.
kostadis: So, okay, what's your plan? Tell me your plan so that I can, uh, figure it all out.
Nikhil: Um, I don't have a concrete plan now, but since we all have the red cloaks, so we are gonna pretend that we, we are Redbrands- Redbrands for some
kostadis: time.
kostadis: Okay. Uh, then, uh, assess the, read the room, then we have to do.
Nikhil: What?
kostadis: The... So since we all have the red cloaks- Mm-hmm ... we'll pretend to be Redbrands for some time,
Nikhil: uh, then see what's happening in the room, read the room, then-
kostadis: Okay. So you're gonna open, you're gonna try to bluff your way through. Correct. All right
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: All right. The bugbears, uh, the bugbears, uh, so the bugbears are sitting there, and they're, like, making their, uh ... Treating the, the go- the goblin, the minute he sees you, just faints.
Nikhil: The goblin?
kostadis: Yes.
Nikhil: Oh, good thing.
kostadis: Yeah. Um, you know, I just get, uh, let me just ... He, he's, like, standing there, and he just kind of faints.
Nikhil: Interesting. I don't have
kostadis: one. Um, the barrack consists four, of four roughly built wooden bunks with heaped blankets and dirty dishes scattered about. A strong smell of unwashed bodies and rotten meat fills the air. Four tally furry homo, humanoids are lounging in the mess, barking orders at a goblin. Your sudden appearance causes the goblin to faint.
Nikhil: Why? What? Why does the goblin
kostadis: faint? Um,
Nikhil: well, it's like
kostadis: just- Okay. I mean, like, I don't, like, um- 11 plus ...
Nikhil: What did I say? I said
kostadis: 11. Yeah, that's what I- Um, in fear
kostadis: He's like afraid of the bugbears and he's afraid of you
kostadis: So, okay, um, I'm confused. Was the goblin, like, a prisoner of the bugbear? You're gonna have to... You don't know. Yeah. Oh, okay. Well, but here's what you do know. You know that they were picking on him. He's got a thing on his head. He does not look like a happy, a goblin.
Nikhil: Okay,
kostadis: okay,
Nikhil: okay.
kostadis: Plus, you know that bugbears and goblins, bugbears are big and are...
kostadis: So in the ecology of the world, the goblins occupy the lowest niche of predators. Okay. Of human-made predators. Mm-hmm. Bugbears occupy a more powerful niche.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: So goblins eventually are, are in those places where the bugbears aren't interested. That doesn't mean they're all bad, it just means that that's where they, their, their niche is-
Nikhil: Yeah
kostadis: below the bugbears.
Nikhil: Okay. Uh,
kostadis: okay, so I walk into the room, uh, I'm gonna talk to the bugbear, you know, this guy, and, um, "What's going on? Uh, how, how are things?" He goes, "Who are you?" "How dare you talk to your master like that?" He, he starts to... He grabs his belly and starts to laugh. Okay, we're done waiting and I talk- Hold on, hold on.
kostadis: Give me a second. He goes, "Leave it to a Redbrand to think he's in charge. Ha ha ha."
Nikhil: I'm gonna bring him to-
kostadis: Hold on, no, no, hold it. Let's, I just wanna make sure you remember something. What you do remember is that Iarno Glasstaff works for somebody. Black Spider. Yes. So this guy is acting as if he knows who the Black Spider is, just-
Nikhil: How we, how we interpret his acting
kostadis: Because he, he basically said that you're acting as if you're in charge, and then he said, "
Nikhil: Leave it to a Redbrand to think they're in charge."
kostadis: Oh, okay. Like it's- Glasstaff leads Redbrand and the bulk bears by the spider
Nikhil: Yes. That's what you're guessing.
kostadis: I'm guessing, yes.
kostadis: Yeah.
Nikhil: You're
kostadis: guessing that they know something more about the spi- the spider. You don't know, but it's just, like, it's a very odd reaction.
Nikhil: Right. Okay.
kostadis: He's, like, laughing at you as if, you know, only, only an idiot would be that stupid. Okay?
kostadis: Okay, yeah. Doesn't make you more powerful or strong, if you will, for that fight. Just keep that in mind. I'm just throwing, throwing a-
Nikhil: You're throwing a bone? You're, you're, you're trying to- Yeah. You're... Oh,
kostadis: that's a
Nikhil: good
kostadis: deception. Roll it, roll with advantage.
kostadis: Uh, that, that, that was with advantage. Still going . Just roll.
Nikhil: Okay. Rolling
kostadis: again. 18. All right.
kostadis: Uh, um, uh
kostadis: Um, but he goes, "Black Spider. We work for Black Spider, and Black Spider, you and you Redbrands work for Black Spider.
Nikhil: Glasstaff works for Black Spider, and don't you forget it."
kostadis: No, we work for Glasstaff.
Nikhil: You work for Glasstaff.
Nikhil: At this point, I-
kostadis: Look,
Nikhil: Black Spider, Black Spider sent us here to take, make sure people like you report to Glasstaff. Don't make me come hit you
kostadis: Keep the arrogance with you also
Nikhil: Okay
kostadis: What was that, sir?
Nikhil: Uh, I'm trying to say what's gonna happen next.
kostadis: Okay. Uh-
Nikhil: You pissed him off
kostadis: Right. Um, um, oh, yeah, yeah. Uh, keep the arrogance with you also, or else, uh, you're gonna be food to the topic.
Nikhil: He, he, he laughs at you. You put me... You threaten me? Iarno Glasstaff needs me to keep you in charge.
kostadis: I feed
Nikhil: you
kostadis: first
kostadis: What are you trying to accomplish? I'm just trying to, you know, understand what's happening. So, uh, where'd you get this, uh, you know, lowly go- goblin? Where'd you find this lowly goblin? Uh...
Nikhil: All right, uh, enough of our defense- No, let
kostadis: go. He go- points to Droop. He goes, he goes, "Droop here is a member of Sawplee, a goblin clan.
kostadis: He walked into hide, into the hideout looking for parts. The Cragmaw want him to join the band." Mm-hmm. So basically the- Yeah, the Cragmaw hideout ... the Cragmaw clan, the Cragmaw goblin clan wants him to join.
Nikhil: Oh. So the, uh, goblin clan wants to join him?
kostadis: Wants Droop to join the clan.
Nikhil: Join the goblin clan?
kostadis: Yes.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: Right?
Nikhil: Oh, but that doesn't explain what he was doing here. He just landed around-
kostadis: Yes, he just la- he just landed here. He m- made a wrong turn. He was looking for something. He should not have been in a place he should not have been looking for.
Nikhil: Okay. Okay.
kostadis: Um, the one thing you do know is the bugbears probably know where the hell the black spider
Nikhil: is.
kostadis: Is? Yes
Nikhil: Um, well, okay, uh, what are you guys doing in this room? Uh, or what's your boss up
kostadis: to? You know, what are you doing for your boss right now in this room?
kostadis: That was a good line. Yeah. What am I doing? I don't know. Hold on. Uh, they, they look at you and goes, "We are, um, um, teaching Droop how to behave." You think Black Spider would be happy with that? Is that what he sent you here for? He goes, "Um, no."
kostadis: What's going on then? So w- if you wanna know, like, where, where is, like, w- w- you know-
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah, I'm trying, I'm just so you know, w- what do you say, trying to, um, rage bait him into telling the truth. What? I'm trying to rage bait him.
kostadis: Rage bait him?
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: Okay. So w- so what is it that you're looking for? Why, why don't we start that way?
kostadis: What do you want, what are you wanting to reveal?
Nikhil: The location of Glasstaff, obviously.
kostadis: Not the... Or, uh, the Black Spider?
Nikhil: Sorry, the Black Spider. You can, you can hook me up. Not Black Staff. Black Spider, yeah. Okay. So one way you could tell him is,
kostadis: like, don't make me go, "I, I don't..." Like, you could... He's not, they're not particularly intelligent creatures, right?
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: So one thing you could try to do is bluff that you know where the Black Spider is
Nikhil: No, I don't think that will work
kostadis: Another thing we could do is try to intimidate them
Nikhil: No, I think that will go the opposite way.
Nikhil: Something like, okay. But, uh-
kostadis: Why don't you get out of this room and take me to your, uh, you know, highly appreciated, uh, you know, highly, uh, yeah, appreciated, uh, Black Spider? You want me to take you to the Black Spider? If you actually work for him, if you actually know his location, then how do I know that you're just using, not using his name, right?
kostadis: That's good. That is good. You could just be using Black Spider. No, that's good. Like, you're, you're, you're... That is, that is a very good angle. Yeah. Um, roll deception or persuasion, whichever one you want
kostadis: Yes, sir.
kostadis: Jewel What? All right, uh, one of your players, one of your fellows helps you. Yeah. Roll again. Oh, don't forget you have ... Yeah, yeah. Don't forget you also have those psychic abilities now.
Nikhil: I do have psychic abilities, but, uh-
kostadis: Not of one, but on other rolls
Nikhil: What?
kostadis: That you can now use, you can now add a B6 number
Nikhil: Oh, right.
Nikhil: Would with any of these things that you're saying?
kostadis: Uh, well, if you have proficiency, you have proficiency in deception. Yes, you do. So if you go to features and traits, go to features and traits
Nikhil: Uh-huh
kostadis: And then go to, uh, keep scrolling down
kostadis: Mm-hmm. Special traits. Keep going down. Yep. Class features. Go to class features. Go, go to class features.
kostadis: No quick smoke, subclass, editing, meta. Did you make sure you're at third level? I am at third level. Level three. Okay.
kostadis: Should have the, the ability. Should have, like, the, the, uh, this ability. No, no. Not that. That's weird.
kostadis: Let me see. We should have the
Nikhil: sneak attack.
kostadis: Oh, you're arcane trickster. I thought you were the psychic. Sorry, my bad. No, no. Uh, you- Yeah, I forgot, forgot, forgot. I'm sorry. I, I forgot you were not. Okay, go. So what would you like? Not
Nikhil: this whole way.
kostadis: All right, so, um-
Nikhil: Yes, uh- All
kostadis: right, roll again. Uh, Sister Maela is going to help you. Okay
kostadis: All right, plus 420. All right. He looks at you and says, "I know where, I know where, uh, Black Spider is." All right, plus two. You don't trust
Nikhil: me? No. Where do you think Black Spider is?
kostadis: I don't know where Black Spider
Nikhil: is- Is that- ...
kostadis: because I work for Glasstaff, unlike you, who is a very good leader, okay? And I just don't use your name like you, uh, use.
kostadis: I don't- unlike you, I don't like, uh, just use my boss's name. He actually lives here, okay?
Nikhil: He, he looks at you and goes like, "Well, Black
kostadis: Spider!" And tells you where Black Spider is.
Nikhil: Yeah, but it's-
kostadis: Yeah, no, no, I figure I'm gonna- Okay. Um, he, he, he, he, you, you successfully bluffed it, man.
Nikhil: Okay,
kostadis: awesome. Hold on.
kostadis: Um, that was, that was Father. I have to admit that was Father. Well done. Rage bait- rage baiting. Rage baiting. Rage baiting prayers. Um, the other two bugbears look at him. Nosk, on the other hand, suddenly goes and realizes he made a terrible mistake, and decides that, uh, the only way to fix the mistake is to kill you.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: But he does... But that's okay 'cause you, uh, because- He actually, what he says is, "And it don't matter that now you know, 'cause now I kill you." All right.
Nikhil: And then Zenvon.
kostadis: Hold on, hold on. Let me just tell you, let me just put this here.
kostadis: Okay. All right,
kostadis: stop that one there
kostadis: All right. Okay. So, um, yes, uh, he goes, "I told you, and now I kill you." Okay. Um, you knew that was gonna happen, right? Yes. So I, I, I, I, I, I mean, I hope I'm not too obvious with this. Thank you for coming back to me. Yeah. Yes. All right. Okay. Uh, let's do initiative
kostadis: No, I'll let go Can I? Yeah, go for it. Eighteen. Oh, nice. Do I have any one to
kostadis: Okay Plus five Plus five. So that's a twenty-three, right? Yep. I think, yeah, I think we also Yeah,
kostadis: yeah. Okay. And, uh, yours, what did we say? Maybe plus point five. Oh, really? Um, tip. You wanna go for him? Yes, please
Nikhil: 12.
kostadis: I don't know if he has more than that. Uh, uh, he has n- he has plus two.
Nikhil: Fourteen.
kostadis: No, he has plus one. Thirteen. Sister Maela has zero.
Nikhil: Fourteen. And
kostadis: Maela. Fifteen. Uh, plus two, right?
Nikhil: Plus two?
kostadis: Yeah. Is it plus two is fifteen? No.
Nikhil: Fifteen plus two is seventeen.
kostadis: Where do I see the capital sheets of these people? Um, I have the, uh, I will send them. I will share them with you.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: All right. Um, let me just see something.
Nikhil: Oh, before we start, I need the help bars.
kostadis: Oh, right, right, right, the help bars
Nikhil: Wait, is that a sweet potato? What? No? No, it's a piece of steak.
kostadis: Why? No, I, uh... This just, that part looks like sweet potato. It does? Yeah, I mean, like, sweet potato and all that.
Nikhil: You like sweet potatoes?
kostadis: Oh, yeah. I love sweet potatoes. Um- Especially in the office, like on Q8, on Wa- Wa- on Entrees Unlimited or some other caterer.
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: They have, uh, sweet potato, uh, not ranch. It's potatoes, sweet potatoes and some chickpea fried kind of thing.
kostadis: Love it. And I've tried making sweet potatoes in the air fryer. You have? It was okay. I must say. It was not as crispy as I expected. Um, there are al- there's all sorts of tricks to doing that.
kostadis: Yeah. I guess you have to boil them or, you know,
kostadis: freeze them or something. I don't know
kostadis: You should try stating the question then putting them there
kostadis: after. All right
kostadis: All right. So let me make sure.
Nikhil: All
kostadis: right, Zenvon, you're up first.
kostadis: So in my turn, I can use spells as well?
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: Uh, we use a Thunderwave. Okay, wait. Where are all these people? Fine. Ten, 15, 20. Okay, I'm at... I have three. So for Thunderwave, um, you see, um... Yeah. You unleash a wave of thunder energy. Each creature in a 15-foot cube originating from you make a constitution saving throw.
kostadis: Right?
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: So I was counting if these are in the 15-foot range.
Nikhil: Uh, so the... Can you go back to the numbers?
kostadis: Uh, 15-foot cube, right?
Nikhil: Yeah. Originating from your
kostadis: Yeah. So, so if you're here, for example, a 15-foot cube- Will cover
Nikhil: the left and the right of, uh, the bunk bed.
kostadis: It'll cover the left or the right, but it won't cover both
Nikhil: No, I think both are 15-foot radius
kostadis: No, no, 15-foot cube is, like, that's the length of an edge
Nikhil: Oh, okay.
Nikhil: Oh.
kostadis: Not a circle
Nikhil: Oh. Oh, yeah.
kostadis: So for example, if you were to go step over here, you could hit the goblin and the two bugbears
Nikhil: No, this says each creature in a 15-foot cube originating
kostadis: from you. Originating from you, does that make any sense? Like-
Nikhil: Yes, that means, like-
kostadis: That means the cube starts at where- wherever I am
Nikhil: Yes
kostadis: Right.
kostadis: So 15 foot this side and 15 foot that side
Nikhil: No. It's cube. It's, it's 15 feet.
kostadis: It's not... That, that would be a 30-foot cube. Just the room- Okay. Okay It's the length of a side
Nikhil: So it's, it's only in one direction?
kostadis: Yeah.
Nikhil: Always?
kostadis: Um, well, you can from-- You can point it anywhere you want. Right. But you can't point it, like, fifteen feet away from you. Right. Okay. Does that make sense? So, like, let's... Here, like, if you put this-- Let's-- Let me just describe this. Like, suppose you drew this rectangle.
kostadis: I'm gonna draw this rectangle.
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: That's a fifteen-foot cube. Right? You can put the fifteen-foot cube over here. You could put the fifteen-foot cube over there. You can basically put it wherever you wanted
Nikhil: Oh, that's a 15-foot cube.
kostadis: Yes.
Nikhil: Interesting. Okay. So I can target the bugbear one and two with that too?
kostadis: Yes. So, so you can, for example, if you didn't wanna hit the goblin, you could target the bugbear one and two like that.
Nikhil: Oh, okay.
kostadis: That make sense?
Nikhil: Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Okay.
kostadis: Yeah. I'm gonna use, uh... Okay, so I'm gonna leave here. Sorry.
Nikhil: Yeah, I'm just
kostadis: saying you could move up one without taking an attack of opportunity.
Nikhil: Well, if I move, uh, one square above, I cannot, uh-
kostadis: No, you can. Because remember, you can put it at, you can point it one foot, you can point it in front of you.
Nikhil: Okay. Okay, cool then. Um, so I'm gonna use the thunderwave.
kostadis: It, it doesn't in- it, it, the square doesn't include you.
Nikhil: Okay. Make sense.
kostadis: It's like, the way to think about it is that the five-foot square, you can put it anywhere you want that touches that five-foot square that you want.
Nikhil: Okay. Okay.
kostadis: Right? So you wanna put it like that, like that, think of it as a circle where you can place this 15-foot cube. Mm-hmm.
Nikhil: That make sense? Makes sense. Yeah.
kostadis: Right. So do you wanna try it on these two bugbears? You wanna include the, the goblin or not?
Nikhil: I don't wanna include the goblin.
kostadis: All right. The two bugbears.
kostadis: Well, uh, let me see. They have to make a saving throw, right?
Nikhil: Yes. Um, yes. So right on.
kostadis: Oh, first of all, uh, let's see what your spell DC. So if you go over in, in your spells, spell DC is a 12. What do I have to roll with dexterity?
Nikhil: Wait, what? DC-
kostadis: It's up over there. See it at the top? Save DC,
Nikhil: that's what I have to beat
kostadis: Save DC. All
Nikhil: right. Now go click on Thunderwave.
kostadis: Uh, Thunderwave is here. Attack save con 12.
Nikhil: Okay. Concentration.
Nikhil: On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 damage.
kostadis: Yes.
Nikhil: On a successful save, uh, nothing happens.
kostadis: All right, so one of the bugbears succeeded, and one of them failed. So how much damage does, uh, this ... How much damage
Nikhil: do they take? This is eight, right?
kostadis: Yes, they roll. You roll it twice
kostadis: M? That's a D10, sorry, that's a D10
Nikhil: Okay. M No, no, no. That's a D10 Oh, so the D10. Okay. D10 does the-
kostadis: Yes. Okay. Looks like two pyramids stacked on top of each other. So Three plus points of damage So
Nikhil: one takes four, the other
kostadis: takes two. Yeah. So this one takes four. He takes four. The other guy takes two. Let me see what happens when I put it away.
kostadis: All
kostadis: right. So this guy takes, uh, four points of damage
kostadis: All right. That was the most impressive thing. All right, Veyra's turn.
Nikhil: Wait, they barely moved, uh-
kostadis: Well, yeah, give me... The first one made a saving throw.
Nikhil: Yeah. Okay.
kostadis: And the second one hit the wall, but I mean, it was, it was a good try.
Nikhil: Their attack isn't as powerful as a scimitar.
kostadis: Well, it could be more powerful, but this was not one of those times.
kostadis: Right. Um, Veyra steps over here and uses a fire bolt
kostadis: That is a hit.
kostadis: And she does eight points of damage on the sketch.
kostadis: All right.
Nikhil: Okay. Next goes the bugbear, bugbear number up-
kostadis: Okay, now there's bugbear
Nikhil: Your bugbear
kostadis: is this? Number three who comes over here.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: He then, uh, just, uh, we just, we see him there. He should be able to- Yeah. All right, he attacks you. Yeah.
kostadis: Uh, with the Morningstar.
Nikhil: Ooh, that's 14 points of damage.
kostadis: 14 points?
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: That's a lot. Uh, I mean, I have about 20, 20 point.
kostadis: I'm down to six.
Nikhil: Yes
kostadis: Um, you don't have to fight them. You could always run away
Nikhil: I can't run away when he's attacking me
kostadis: You can always disengage and run
Nikhil: But that's only during my turn
kostadis: Yeah, and I'm just saying, like, you guys, you don't have to fight this combat to the end is what I'm trying to say. Um,
Nikhil: meanwhile- We'll fight the bugbears until the end
kostadis: Yes, you, yes, you don't...
kostadis: There's no-
Nikhil: Because we got the information out of it
kostadis: Yes, and just, I just want to make sure you know that
Nikhil: No, but you know the, the reasoning we gave initially was like, you know, these people might-
kostadis: Yeah, I know that, but you being dead is even worse. Yeah. I'm just saying. Uh, okay. Okay, so he imposes, uh, Pip imposes disa- what's your armor class?
kostadis: 14. No, that doesn't work. All right
kostadis: Okay. Uh, let's see what happens. What are we gonna do next? Sister Maela. Sister Maela goes, "Medic!" And, um-
Nikhil: Need, uh, healing potions ...
kostadis: uh, she, uh, throws you, she casts a cure light, uh, cure light wound You get seven more hit points
Nikhil: Six plus seven, 13
kostadis: Right
Nikhil: Went down to nothing
kostadis: This bugbear goes, "You think you smarter than bugbears?"
kostadis: And hits you
Nikhil: Why me? Okay
kostadis: Why? Because he hates you
Nikhil: I rage baited him too
kostadis: much. I think I rage baited him too much
Nikhil: Yeah, I think you rage baited him. Uh, you take 11 points of damage
kostadis: Oh, fuck. Okay. Nine, 10, 11, 13, minus seven is what I got All
Nikhil: right.
kostadis: Pip steps forward and besides this here. Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
kostadis: Maybe, maybe the, uh, yeah. Uh, Pip steps forward and thwacks the bugbear.
kostadis: And he's got his new, uh, sword. He missed
kostadis: Uh, he misses. All right, bugbear 11. The other bugbear, bugbear number two steps forward and swings at Pip
kostadis: And misses. And on the fourth, Babir tosses his javelin at it. And misses again. All right. Zenvon, you're up. No, there's another- No, I, I bid all them. I, I, I b- I bid them all. Okay. Zenvon, you're up
kostadis: This guy, probably wanna try to kill him with ... You can either use your arrow to try to kill this guy, or use your-
Nikhil: I currently have, like, two hit points. Okay. So, uh-
kostadis: You wanna drink one of your potions of healing?
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: Okay. So, um, what you do is you go to the inventory, party inventory.
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: Go to inventory, go to party inventory.
Nikhil: Party inventory? Yeah. Okay.
kostadis: Mm-hmm. You have a potion of healing.
Nikhil: What do I do?
kostadis: Just, uh,
Nikhil: done?
kostadis: Yes. Equip one. You can say, roll 2D4 plus 2
kostadis: Just roll 2D4 plus two. That's how much you need once you get back.
Nikhil: This is D4?
kostadis: Yes. Uh, let me see. Oh, that is a D4.
kostadis: Two. Five, so 20 points. You can also disengage, I believe
kostadis: Yeah. Um, no, no, no. Uh, not disengage, right? I can, um-
Nikhil: You can't drink a
kostadis: potion and attack
Nikhil: Oh. Okay. Disengage.
kostadis: D- disengaging from the back means you can fight, hit with your arrows.
Nikhil: Yeah. Okay.
kostadis: All right? Okay. Veyra. When did she get... What happens when Veyra gets to the third level?
kostadis: Right. Uh, she will cast a second level magical she-- a magic missile To my devil's John? Yes. Fourth wisdom. So she does, uh, eight points of damage on this guy. Right
kostadis: And she's like, "Uh, I don't think we're doing so well by his boss."
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: Uh, the bugbear.
Nikhil: Can we not just close the door and leave?
kostadis: Uh, you can tell Pit to do that.
Nikhil: And, like, burn the room somehow? Is that possible?
kostadis: Um, I mean, you, you do have oil, I presume. You could light oil and throw it in there.
Nikhil: Check what inventory I have.
kostadis: All right, check your inventory. All right, so the bugbear swings and misses on Pit. All right. Sister Maela And over there. She's going to use her spell. Oh, yeah. I have seven ounces of oil and a tinderbox. Tinderbox is- I think the mic, please ... matchbox kind
Nikhil: of thing. Mm-hmm.
kostadis: A small container holding flint, fire steel, and tinder.
kostadis: Literally dry clumps of thin light oil used to kindle a fire. Okay, perfect. Yeah, cool
kostadis: Yes. What? Mass damage. Uh, you know, pour oil in the room. Uh, in the finger dungeon. So it was good. Okay.
Nikhil: Uh-
kostadis: I'm done with these guys. I don't care about the goblin. All right, you're just gonna try to run
Nikhil: away?
kostadis: What?
Nikhil: Close the door and run away?
kostadis: No, burn them all. Yeah, but they're gonna
Nikhil: try to
kostadis: open
Nikhil: the
kostadis: door.
Nikhil: Lock it.
Nikhil: I mean, I will lock it.
kostadis: Okay,
Nikhil: but...
kostadis: And leave, not just stay there.
kostadis: Yeah, yeah. I mean, like, poke your feet far and, like, l- light, light up the room and run away. Okay. So I'm just trying to see what, like... Okay. So all right. So this bugbear, um, so, uh, let's try.
kostadis: Sure.
kostadis: All right. Another bugbear.
Nikhil: So, I mean, just to make sure the goblin is useless, right? It's just a- Yeah,
kostadis: but it sees, at this point in time, it said that you are the bo- goblins
kostadis: All right. Bugbear, this bugbear. He'll try to nuke. Nosk tries to hit Pip again, uh, and misses. All right. Pip, uh, what you want to, you want him to step outside? Yeah. All right, so Pip is gonna take one whack at this guy,
kostadis: and hits
kostadis: All right, hold on now. That is new plus three. Which takes four points of damage. All right. Hip steps over here and takes an attack of opportunity- Mm-hmm ... and misses, um,
kostadis: as he slams the door shut. All right Bugbear number, oh, the next bugbear, seeing the door slam shut-
Nikhil: Mm-hmm. Tries to attack him ...
kostadis: um, actually tries to smash it with his hand axe. Hits for,
kostadis: for 15 points of damage. The door is pretty damaged
kostadis: It's not broken yet. All right, then the next bugbear decides to, uh, swing at the door, and he, you know, misses, you know, doesn't hit it very well.
Nikhil: Wait.
kostadis: Missing it is not the right word. All right, Zenvon.
Nikhil: Zenvon.
kostadis: Okay. So, um, what do you wanna do?
Nikhil: Okay. So
kostadis: in my inventory I have, like, seven bottles of oil.
Nikhil: All right.
kostadis: Right.
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: Um, and I have a tinderbox.
Nikhil: Okay. You wanna throw all that oil in there?
kostadis: So, uh, spread all of that oil in front of the door, on the door, like, pour it from under the door into the room. Right. Use the tinderbox. And run. The tinderbox. A tinderbox is
kostadis: a small container of fire.
Nikhil: Which you can light, which you can light with your mage hand.
kostadis: Usually dry cloth soaked in light, o- light oil.
Nikhil: Right. So yeah, use the tinderbox. I'm gonna light it up with my mage hand and then-
kostadis: Okay, so- ...
Nikhil: go far away.
kostadis: So, so telling everybody to run... So, okay, so you go over here. I'm presuming you're, you're doing that, and you tell everybody else to go.
Nikhil: Okay. Yes. Where do you
kostadis: want? Yeah, I'm just... Like, where do you go?
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: Just put yourself where you are. Well, this is the only access I have. I think north, no, beyond this. Okay Yeah, I can't move my character here, but-
Nikhil: You can't?
kostadis: Yeah, I can. But now I can. Now I can, yes. Uh, right. So yeah, I move. I wanna move myself here.
kostadis: I wanna tell everybody to come over here, but right up here. Okay. Well, it's okay. So, so we should... Okay. So you, you set up everything like that. All right. Veyra follows you. All right
kostadis: Uh, this bugbear tries to smash the door again.
kostadis: Hits the door
kostadis: He smashed into the door and it breaks into a lot of pieces. Sister Maela runs over here. Mm-hmm. Uh-
Nikhil: It, it gets to open the door.
kostadis: Yeah, 'cause it hasn't been his turn yet.
Nikhil: Okay. Probably.
kostadis: This d- this bugbear, uh, sees Pip and swings and misses, swing at him, and misses. Right. I'm presuming Pip disengages and runs?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah. Yeah, he disengages and runs. He
kostadis: disengages and runs. All right. Um-
kostadis: This bug here comes out
kostadis: Um, what do we do? The water on the rocks. It's all slick. No, he's gonna come one, two, three
Nikhil: No, just, just to, uh, make, have you see, uh, there's oil all over this wa- hallway. There's oil underneath the door going-
kostadis: Okay. And I'm just trying to think. I'm just trying to think. All right, so I'm gonna say it's di- difficult terrain, so he can move o- up till there
Nikhil: But that's like coming down towards-
kostadis: And, and, yeah, I'm just saying he's moving at half speed
Nikhil: Yeah, he's slipping.
kostadis: Well, that's why you only move at
Nikhil: half speed Ah, yes.
kostadis: Right?
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: This guy moves over here, right? He moves. All right, Zenvon, you're gonna light it up. All right. All right. Um, okay
kostadis: Map description. Let me
kostadis: Okay, so it causes five points of damage, so this guy dies
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: All right? And the other ones take five points of damage each
Nikhil: In the room? Yeah,
kostadis: yeah.
Nikhil: That's it?
kostadis: Yes.
Nikhil: So they don't die from the fire?
kostadis: No, they do not die from the fire, but-
Nikhil: Oh, shit. I was expecting all of them to die
kostadis: Yeah, no, that wasn't gonna happen.
kostadis: But you, you, they're now, you now can run away
kostadis: They're also wounded
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah. Okay.
kostadis: Oh, I mean, you, you- they're also
Nikhil: wounded.
kostadis: Okay. Yeah, yeah. I can totally hear that.
Nikhil: All right.
kostadis: Okay. The feature and available for you. And, uh-
Nikhil: You got what you wanted?
kostadis: Yes. Uh, we'll dash through the main entrance.
Nikhil: You're gonna dash across this way? So just show me where you're going.
kostadis: Um
kostadis: Okay, again, I have to go here. Yeah, we have to go into the- No,
Nikhil: you can go across.
kostadis: You can go through here. Like here? Yeah. Yeah, I'm gonna... Oh, yeah, yeah.
Nikhil: Right, right. Yeah, yeah. So, so, yes, uh, I'm gonna go this way, this way, this way. All
kostadis: right, you're gonna- you're going to run. Yes?
Nikhil: Yes. All
kostadis: right, so move. Okay, so let's see you move 60 feet.
Nikhil: 60 feet.
kostadis: 90 feet actually, 'cause you're, you, you, you dash. All right, we'll assume you got over there. All right. Uh, the nothic-
Nikhil: Yeah ...
kostadis: the nothic comes over here and goes Flambé
Nikhil: Where is he?
kostadis: Okay.
Nikhil: Thanks, flambé
kostadis: flambé. What does it mean? Can I order it more?
Nikhil: Flambé? It means cooked food.
kostadis: Cooked food. Okay. Yeah. Okay. Okay.
Nikhil: Like flambé. Yeah. Okay. Yes. It has its food. It's not gonna hurt us.
kostadis: Well, no, it, it, it, it, it looks at you, and as it's running, as you're running away- Uh-huh
kostadis: Okay, so,
kostadis: um, Ssarnak looks the creature Ssarnak? Yes, he calls himself, he introduces himself as Ssarnak
Nikhil: Oh
kostadis: And he whispers And all of a sudden, uh, what's her name, is very pale in the face. "Your teacher is not dead. He is not in a place where dead is easy."
kostadis: Oh, that's
Nikhil: just to
kostadis: Maela. No, uh, to Veyra. Veyra,
Nikhil: Veyra, yeah, yeah. "Your teacher is not dead. He is not in a place where dead is easy."
Nikhil: Do we engage with, uh, the thing?
kostadis: That, I mean, I, I'm just telling you what he does. You don't have to do anything at this point. All right. Great. Yeah, yeah. All right. So, um, all right. So Veyra is, um, freaked out, and, uh, she's gonna wanna go talk to this guy unless you do something to try to... Un- unless, uh, Pip and Sister Maela convince her not to do it.
kostadis: So do you wanna have Sister Maela try to convince her not to go talk to the, the moth folk?
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: Okay, so roll a persuasion
kostadis: Like, okay, that- okay, hold on, hold on. Uh, no, that, uh, Veyra is not convinced. Just gonna go talk. She's gonna go, "I got to go talk to him." All right. Sister Maela can use, can attempt to grapple her.
kostadis: That's when you grab somebody.
Nikhil: Right, right. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah. Uh-huh.
kostadis: You gonna try to grapple her?
Nikhil: Yes. To
kostadis: prevent her from going? Okay.
kostadis: Uh, you succeeded in grapple.
Nikhil: Okay, great.
kostadis: All right, so Veyra is sort of like screaming, "I gotta go talk to him. I've gotta go talk to him." All right. The bugbear, the bugbear takes another five points of damage, and this is still difficult terrain. There we go. Okay, but he takes another five points of damage.
kostadis: He's screaming at the top of his lungs, bloody cursing hell. All right. Sister Maela. Sister Maela drags, um-
kostadis: Drags Veyra and herself over here. Then the other
kostadis: bugbear comes out wide. He takes another five points of damage.
kostadis: All right, now Pip. Is that right? Pip Not
Nikhil: Pip, Zenvon
kostadis: What? No, but then he already did his thing. Uh, Pip runs 30 feet and runs another 30 feet Okay And gets over here. All right. Yeah All right
Nikhil: The bugbear takes another bite point
kostadis: That bugbear
kostadis: Bugbear. The next bugbear takes another five points of damage, and the fire burns out. Mm-hmm. All right
Nikhil: Fire burns out?
kostadis: Yeah. It, it takes two rounds to burn out. What?
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: Hold on, let me just check before I say that.
Nikhil: No, I have, like, seven pounds of oil.
kostadis: Right. So, like, how much, how long does a pound of oil
kostadis: All right, so the short answer is to get seven... You can only cover five feet with it That's a pound of oil, just five feet? Uh, hold on. Let me see how much seven pounds is.
kostadis: How much- Three kilos. How much... Hold on. I have to think. I, dude, I have to think of this, right? Close to three liters of oil. Uh, how many pints? Pints? No. How many pints oil in a pound of oil in conversion?
kostadis: Okay, so according to standard rules, one pint equals one pound One
Nikhil: pint is equal? One pound
kostadis: One pound. Right. So I'm just gonna say by-
Nikhil: One pints ...
kostadis: yeah, so, so, so if you roll, if you put all of the pints, all of the, all, so if you covered, if you used half the area, I'm just gonna say you, you br- y- you covered all the area so that they got burned
Nikhil: Yeah
kostadis: All right?
kostadis: Yeah So now it, it's stopped burning. But that's okay. You've almost run out of the w- you've almost run out. Yeah, okay Um, so, uh, all right. Zenvon, uh, Sister Maela screams, "Uh, the fire went out." Okay. So then we're gonna have to rush Uh, so, so you're telling her to rush, not, not talk?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah.
kostadis: Okay, but she's alone there and they're going to catch up with her.
Nikhil: She's not alone. Where is she?
kostadis: Uh, okay, so let me just... I, I just really can't see her. Let me fix that.
Nikhil: Yeah, I thought she was scared.
kostadis: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no
kostadis: Okay. You just check it out? Okay.
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Right, so she now sees the... Oh, she's, like, basically screaming for help. Zenvon, are you gonna come help her?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah, I'm gonna come back.
kostadis: All right, you're gonna come back, help her.
Nikhil: Thanks.
kostadis: Okay. Hey, do you wanna use your arrow against them?
kostadis: But, uh, short bow. Short bow would probably be a good thing.
Nikhil: Short bow, yeah.
kostadis: Nice. All right I, what's five, 14?
Nikhil: Uh, that is a miss.
kostadis: That's a miss?
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: Okay. Yeah.
Nikhil: That's fine. Um...
kostadis: Well, I don't have,
Nikhil: uh, a nick property, right? I think I can-
kostadis: With the shortbow? The
Nikhil: shortbow. No?
kostadis: No, the shortbow does not have that.
Nikhil: Only the shortbow.
kostadis: It has... Yeah, it doesn't have that.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: That's fine.
Nikhil: Fine, yeah. Okay.
kostadis: It's fine.
Nikhil: That's fine.
kostadis: Um, Veyra has, uh, calmed down and realizing that, you know, maybe going to ask a murderous eating creature-
kostadis: You know, help is perhaps not the best idea she has, so she runs like crazy.
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: All right.
kostadis: This bugbear
kostadis: dashes over here
Nikhil: Oh, okay.
kostadis: Sister Maela, because he dashed, Sister Maela can disengage or she can take a, her chance on a reaction. What would you like her to do?
Nikhil: Disengage.
kostadis: Disengage?
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: All right. She disengage. One, two, three, four, five
kostadis: All right, she gets there we go. All right.
kostadis: This Budvir.
kostadis: Right over here. He dashes over here All right. Pip shouts, "Boss, you okay?"
Nikhil: Yeah, but I'm being, uh, chased.
kostadis: You can, you can, you can disengage and run away from them.
Nikhil: Yes, I'm being chased, so I'll do the same disengage and- Oh, it's not your
kostadis: turn yet. Oh, shit. Okay. No, I'm
Nikhil: just,
kostadis: I'm just asking. I'm- Pip's asking what he should do.
Nikhil: Um...
kostadis: You want him to hold the door closed?
Nikhil: Yeah. To the machine Okay.
kostadis: Where's the door, by the way?
Nikhil: It's right here
kostadis: This one? Oh, yeah. Okay, that's a door. Okay, cool. Uh, I want him to hold the door when I dash.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: So, uh- That side? Yeah. All right. Zenvon, dash.
Nikhil: Yes. Okay, good. Did
kostadis: you dash? I did. All right. Uh, Veyra is behind the door.
kostadis: This bugbear. Another here
kostadis: He takes a whack at that Sister Maela, and fortunately misses.
Nikhil: Hey, I was so scared like- ... I could pass the door or
kostadis: not. What, what?
Nikhil: No, uh, only she is the one left behind the door.
kostadis: Yeah. Right? She, yeah, so she runs and closes the door-
Nikhil: Awesome ...
kostadis: and locks it.
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: That door is closed and locked.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: All right.
kostadis: Bugbears arrive and are going to start banging at that door too.
Nikhil: So we run away at this point.
kostadis: All right.
Nikhil: Towards the manor's entrance.
kostadis: All right, so okay. So I'm going to... You guys run away. Like, let me just see how long it takes the bugbears to break the door.
kostadis: Right. It takes them three rounds to break the door, which is more than enough time for you guys to escape.
Nikhil: Yeah. So we come out.
kostadis: You come out. And I presume, um, you're going to get as far from Tresendar Manor as possible.
Nikhil: Yeah,
kostadis: yeah. All right.
kostadis: Uh, stop the, uh, we can stop the Kravaos music. Yes. Enjoy that?
Nikhil: I did, yeah. Okay, I have a question.
kostadis: Yes. What is, uh, Black Spider's location? Yeah.
Nikhil: Oh, I, I
kostadis: showed you. I showed you. It was on the map.
Nikhil: You showed me? No.
kostadis: Yeah, I did.
Nikhil: No.
kostadis: I put it on the map. Okay. Scroll up
kostadis: Oh, Cragmaw guide. Under tree. It's there. Mm-hmm. It's a bit easier to see. Does that get easier to see? Yeah. Yeah.
kostadis: All right. Yeah, that's where he is.
Nikhil: Wow.
kostadis: He's at the Cragmaw Castle.
Nikhil: He is at the Cragmaw Castle or close to the Cragmaw Castle, somewhere behind somewhere?
kostadis: Uh, Cragmaw Castle. I'm telling you that he's in the Cragmaw Castle All right. All right, you manage to jump out of the...
kostadis: You manage to jump out the crescendo. That's one more
Nikhil: minutes. Hmm.
Nikhil: That's five seconds.
kostadis: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: All right.
Nikhil: That was intense.
kostadis: It was intense, actually. I didn't, uh- That was, that was a little bit more intense than I thought it would be. Well, perceptions. Uh
Nikhil: All right. Okay. Uh. Uh.
kostadis: All right
kostadis: So Pip, Veyra turns to Pip Bring it on, toaster. Okay And she goes, "The stone you sold, describe it to me." If you remember what happened with everybody. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Just not what it looked like, what it felt like whole. Uh, what it felt like to hold
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Now, you'll remember, have a black stone in your pocket. Are you gonna tell her that you have it or not?
Nikhil: Do I have a black stone?
kostadis: Yes, you picked it up when you, when, when the, the very beginning when you guys were going over the cart. Remember how you saw the black obelisk?
Nikhil: Right.
kostadis: That was a black stone.
Nikhil: The one that I picked it up?
kostadis: Yes. Okay.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: Are you gonna tell her that you have it or not?
Nikhil: Um, gonna tell her.
kostadis: You're gonna tell her?
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: Uh, all right. Uh, she goes, "Oh." And then she takes her black, her blue crystal and points it, and her crystal lights even brighter. So what then? So whatever this black stone is, it's c- it's connected.
Nikhil: With what?
kostadis: You don't know.
Nikhil: Just, I don't know?
kostadis: Uh, Veyra, Veyra knows that her advisor was really into all of this. Okay. Right? And what she knows about her advisor-
kostadis: Uh, machine or other advisor. Um
kostadis: So what she knows about her advisor is that her advisor is Orryn Voss, and that he had a theory about how there was some kind of device that was doing something really bizarre and controlling people. And she's got all sorts of theories, conspiracies, strange monsters that nobody's heard of all hooked up together.
kostadis: Quite honestly, when you first heard it, it sounded like Well, the kind of thing people believe but isn't-
Nikhil: Yeah,
kostadis: yeah.
Nikhil: Hard backup, but-
kostadis: Hey, but back, no, you know, but now, you know, there's, like, the second rock that's glowing, right? And you've seen the goblet- You have seen the goblins with the sh- the faces.
kostadis: Remember you saw the, the... I don't remember what you would call this, but there were the, the goblin, you, you saw these two goblin skulls. Remember how you heard that from, um... What's his name? From Sildar.
Nikhil: Sildar. Yeah.
kostadis: Right? That he'd been interviewed by these goblins with the strange bodies, right?
Nikhil: Right, right.
kostadis: Right. You saw two of those goblins, dead goblins, in the crevasse.
Nikhil: Okay. Okay.
kostadis: Right? So there, those, that wasn't just his impression. There's some-
Nikhil: Something-
kostadis: Something, something odd going on.
Nikhil: Okay. Seems like everything is connecting.
kostadis: Yes.
Nikhil: Okay. All
kostadis: right. So-
Nikhil: So it's making, uh, whatever Veyra is believing in, like, much stronger.
kostadis: Yes.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: You, you're starting to... Like, so you have to decide whether you're believing her more or less now.
Nikhil: I believe her more.
kostadis: You're gonna believe her more. Do you tell her that or do you keep that to yourself?
Nikhil: I keep that to myself.
kostadis: Okay. That's fair. Then you trust her more.
Nikhil: Yeah. Or,
kostadis: or you trust her more.
kostadis: All right. Yes. Okay. Um, all right. Veyra, uh... Meanwhile, Sister Maela looks a little bit cheesed.
Nikhil: Cheesed?
kostadis: Upset.
Nikhil: Upset. Oh, okay.
kostadis: I mean, now that you... Okay. Roll an insight or an investigation
Nikhil: It's us.
kostadis: Four, ten. Ten. All right, you get nothing. All right. You don't, you have no insight into why she might be cheesed. But you, but she does have a sour expression on her face. All right.
kostadis: All right Right.
kostadis: So we going back to Phandalin to rest? Yes. Because, uh, like it's night and we're tired. Yes. When we put in.
kostadis: All right. Now, okay, so you arrive in Phandalin.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: All right. And so I'm just, I'm just trying to catch up with what happened next. That's why you saw me sort of-
kostadis: Yeah. Um, all right, so you arrive in Phandalin, so let's get the Phandalin music playing and-
kostadis: Yeah. Music up the street. What? Is this like playing as we walking? No, I'm just like- Yeah, cool. Yeah. Okay. You know, it's just like, it's just- After a long battle, I don't wanna deal with, uh, welcoming people. I just wanna go anywhere. All right, so where would you like to go?
Nikhil: Stonehill Inn, or do I have a place to sleep?
kostadis: All right, so there's a couple of things that, you know, gonna pop into your head. One was that Wick said that... So there's a couple of open quests you have. So let me just, uh, let me just, uh... I, I wanted to... I did actually create the head quests list for you. Okay. Make sure it's correct
kostadis: Okay. Uh, let's see this one.
kostadis: These are, I don't know how well they're gonna be generated, so be aware of that. Um, yeah
kostadis: Actually, you can see it now.
Nikhil: That's clock.
kostadis: So this is where it helps? Yes. Yeah, there are only six nodes. Correct. Right.
kostadis: They did not clear my own. Oh, is it because of the bug fix and the- Yeah ... monster?
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: Right.
kostadis: So the hero can pass Okay. Okay.
Nikhil: So I can choose any of these after this?
kostadis: Yes. But you've just come back from trusting your minor, and there's one detail that you do know. Wick implied that Iarno was getting orders from somebody.
Nikhil: Like, by who?
kostadis: Yes, in Phandalin
Nikhil: No, Iarno was getting orders from Black Spider, right? Not someone in Phandalin
kostadis: But I'm just telling you that's what you think. That's what you believe. Wick li-
Nikhil: Well, I'm just correlating two things
kostadis: Yes. I'm, I'm just telling you, Wick did mention that
Nikhil: But you're saying there is a possibility that, um, Iarno could be getting orders from two people, one is Black Spider and the other one is someone else from Phandalin?
kostadis: Yes Well, okay. I, I'm just... I, I just wanted to make sure- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ... you, you don't and are able to- All right ... or, or he might be just some dude who was trying to impress you
Nikhil: Right
kostadis: Like, you, you don't know. And, and you did kill him, so-
Nikhil: Mm-hmm ...
kostadis: you, you probably will never know
Nikhil: Mm-hmm
kostadis: All right. Just wanted to make sure you knew that
Nikhil: Cool.
Nikhil: Yes
Nikhil: All right. Well, who do you wanna go to first? All right, I presume you're gonna go to the inn to take a rest?
kostadis: Yes, yes.
Nikhil: All right. See that that's-
kostadis: You head back to the inn.
Nikhil: Yep
kostadis: All right. And, uh, Toblen, you head to the to-- uh, anything there? Oh, yeah.
kostadis: Maybe it's Toblen. Uh, six. Am I seeing anything I didn't notice previously? Um, okay. So I think could be in
kostadis: No, it's not. That is a good inn. All right, um, you arrive into the inn, and Elsa, Tuck, Toblen are here, in addition to, uh, Freda and Narth, whom we've met in the past.
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Um, those are people you've spoken to in the past. I'm gonna put you back
kostadis: Right? They're, uh, drinking, they're drinking Yeah. Clearly Redbrand co- commoner is not here. Uh, Sildar is sitting at the table. He sees you arrive. Mm-hmm. You look bloodied, bruised, and bowed. Um, what do you tell him? You can even tell him tomorrow, man
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah. I'm, uh, I'm gonna tell him I need to rest. Yeah.
kostadis: He, he, he, he, he... All right, so you go upstairs to get a rest. Um, goblin, uh, goblin shouts, "Uh, since you guys did a, since you guys did us a good deed with the, uh, Redbrand, tonight's free."
Nikhil: Thank you. Thank you, Toblen.
kostadis: Yep, you're very welcome. You're very- So
Nikhil: could you send us some food-
kostadis: Food? ... up to the room, please?
kostadis: Uh, because I said room was free, not board.
Nikhil: Well, yeah, I'll pay for the food.
kostadis: All right. So, uh, subtract, uh, 10 silver pieces for the food.
Nikhil: From that.
kostadis: Where it went. Yeah, just go there. Click on the coins. Oh. No, they're there. Top Party inventory Both Yes. Yeah. And then just go scroll down and just put 10 silver pieces and click remove.
kostadis: There. That's it. Okay. Got it? Cheapest accounting ever. Nice. All right. Awesome. Morning arrives. Everybody long rested? Okay, so I would click this then. Yes
kostadis: No, okay, that's good to
kostadis: go on here. Okay.
kostadis: Like it.
Nikhil: All right.
kostadis: Wait, what happened? What?
Nikhil: What happened?
kostadis: No, I'm clicking this. This can't- No, click.
Nikhil: You have to confirm it.
kostadis: Okay. Fine.
Nikhil: All right. Um, you come
kostadis: down and Sildar is, uh, pleased to see you. Says, "Do you have any news?"
kostadis: You, you know that, you, you know it happened to Iarno
Nikhil: I know what happened to him. We got out of there
kostadis: Yeah. R- go read the quest log so you know what the... Read the, read the quest log so you know what the deal was and then Very top.
kostadis: Oh, okay. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Your own agent is the one who is behind most of the bad deals and kind of, you know, misinformation. You are not able to trust, yeah
kostadis: Do you
Nikhil: have any proof?
kostadis: You have a note. You remember you found a
Nikhil: note on your desk from the Black Spider?
kostadis: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah, I have a note that I found in the Tresendar manor that, that, uh, proves that he is, uh, that, uh, he was ... Black Spider addressed him with his first name. He looks at it.
kostadis: He's appalled. He goes, he, he looks at you and says, "Well, this was not the reward I was hoping for when I signed it, but I did offer a reward, did I not?" You did. And by the terms of the reward-
Nikhil: Uh, he goes, "Very well. Here is the rest of your treasure."
kostadis: Okay. So wait, I don't remember negotiating with him for more.
Nikhil: Yes, I don't remember that negotiation
kostadis: On my wall, we can, uh, we can infer it. Hold on.
Nikhil: Oh, yeah. I went, waited the camera and offered a bit to go to useful expert and have a- No,
kostadis: no, no. This is for the, this is for the, um, the, the, the, the quest from Sildar, right?
Nikhil: Yeah.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Nikhil: All right,
kostadis: all right, all right. So it was, uh, 250 gold pieces for eliminating the Redbrand threat and finding Iarno. Okay.
Nikhil: All
kostadis: right. A hundred-- You, you convinced him to give you a hundred up front. Okay.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: So he gives you another 150.
kostadis: All right? So add 150 to your treasure
Nikhil: And then 15 gore points?
kostadis: Um, yeah, gore points. Yes.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: All right. He says, "You have done well." He go, he looks at you and he goes, "For someone of your background- Mm-hmm. "You have done well."
kostadis: Thank you. Uh, I some unknown to, like, you know, except my background, if you can say that I, I, I can-- You get the impression that, you know, he's, like, trying really hard not to say somebody who was born on the wrong side of the tracks. Without the right bloodlines.
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: He's trying really hard not to say all that.
kostadis: Right. You, you can see him. You, you, you can see him visibly- He's trying to acknowledge my success without being condescending of my- Yeah, yeah. He's trying really, really hard. Yes, I get that. Okay, just wanted to be clear. Um, he does say that, "Well,
Nikhil: I need you to find the Iarno and deal with him."
kostadis: Do you think about leaving me? Do you want me to kill him or bring him back to you alive, or?
Nikhil: And he goes, "I would prefer that you capture him so that we can take him to Neverwinter so he can face trial for his crimes." Prefer.
kostadis: Well, you know, your preference could fail at many points before he reaches the trial with Neverwinter, so, uh-
Nikhil: He says-
kostadis: think about it again. It's, it's very, uh, tedious job to bring him alive. There will be more money in it if he was brought back alive. That's pretty well twice as much There's another 200 gold pieces if you bring him back alive, 100 if he's dead. 50 if we can't raise him. 50
Nikhil: if we can?
kostadis: Cannot raise him from the dead.
Nikhil: Raise him.
Nikhil: Is that possible with, I mean-
kostadis: Yes, if you, for example, if somebody cuts off his head, he can't be raised from the dead
Nikhil: Well, we'll keep the options open with the-
kostadis: So is that a no?
Nikhil: No, I mean, I don't know if he's gonna be ali- if I'm gonna bring him alive or dead, so I'm gonna bring him to you.
kostadis: One way or the other?
Nikhil: One way or the other. He
kostadis: goes, "Well..." He pauses and said, "I would not be upset if he paid that debt." Okay. "But I have bosses who
Nikhil: would be."
Nikhil: Do I tell Black Spider or he does not care about other things? Well, he's under the
kostadis: Lords Alliance. He's-- Think of him as somebody who... So the l- the way to think about the Lords Alliance is that they-- So, so think about, so let's think about the factional groups. The Lords Alliance is essentially the, the Sword Coast in the north is a series of city-states.
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Right? Each one of those city-states have some kind of ruling group. The collection of all those city-states and all the lords that run them is called the Lords Alliance. So do they care about threats to their power? Absolutely. Okay, so, so would he care about this? Yes. Right
kostadis: It's all about the order and, and pulling things together Well, since you're the melithil also, like, so I think countering, uh, outbreak Could be of slightly less important because he gets orders from Black Spider Who is the Black Spider? We don't know yet, but there's, there's a boss to Albrek who gives some orders and he just executes them.
kostadis: So y- if you think the crime's gonna stop if you catch Albrek, then it's not. But if you just want to, you know, fulfill your personal vengeance, then I'm happy to
kostadis: help with that. Awesome.
kostadis: That was very well done. Very well done. Iarno steps back and says ... Oh, sorry. Uh, Sildar steps back and says, "Defeating whoever is behind Iarno is more important than capturing Iarno," pauses and then says, "But if Iarno fled as he said, then the most likely place for him to have fled was to his boss. So perhaps we will get two birds with one stone."
kostadis: Well, that's a possibility. Or, you know- Iarno could be killed by his boss knowing that he has failed him
Nikhil: In which case, you will just find his
kostadis: body
Nikhil: Right. At that point, I will just give my money.
kostadis: He pauses and goes, "50 if I can't raise him from the dead."
Nikhil: Oh, right. Yeah.
kostadis: 50 gold pieces if he can't be raised from the dead, 100 if he can be raised from the dead, and 200-
Nikhil: If he's alive
kostadis: if he's alive.
Nikhil: Well, okay. I'm gonna negotiate at
kostadis: this time. 20, 50, and 100. All right, let's just make s- let's just make a note of that so we don't forget
kostadis: All right.
kostadis: Okay. So... I don't get something. What am I doing? Right. All right. Okay. So, um, you now have a bunch of open quests. Good. Um, you also wanna know whether ... You also have this opportunity to go ask some people and see if they were giving orders to, um, Iarno.
Nikhil: And where do I go ask people?
kostadis: Well, so remember, you wanna
kostadis: Do, do, are, do, have you accepted the idea that Iarno wasn't getting orders from anybody in Phandalin?
Nikhil: No, I did not. No, I did not 'cause that's a possibility that I still-
kostadis: Right. So the one person you did notice that was talking to the Redbrand was Halia. Halia, yeah. Yeah.
Nikhil: Right.
kostadis: Yeah. Who tried to act innocent.
Nikhil: Yes. You wanna go check her out?
kostadis: Oh, yeah, yeah. So, um, since I'm carrying a jade frog with gold eyes, and Halia might know the price- Mm. I would wanna, you know, just pay a visit and see- You want to pay a visit to Halia? Halia, yes. To see, uh, to, to get a quote on this, the price for the brown micro frog. Okay. So yeah, just, just business, right?
kostadis: Just business. Just business.
kostadis: And there's a bit with, uh, that guy there. It'd be easy to go. All right. Okay. So I have a question. You see in the quest notes?
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Below Halia's invitation, there is the Shrine of Luck. Yes. Where the Acolyte of Tymora said she has worked for us- Yes ... after Gundren is home. Not-- Oh, okay. Can we, can we... Okay, until Gundren is home, I cannot know what the
Nikhil: work is. Uh. Yeah. Okay. You read that? Yeah. What, what does it say in the end? Just don't forget the details sometimes. It is, it was generated, right?
kostadis: The Shrine of Luck. The Acolyte of Tymora said she has worked for us after Gundren is
kostadis: home. I'm just making sure. It's fine. Wonderful
kostadis: Oh, okay. So actually what this was was it was earlier when they thought Gundren was with Ra- was with Sildar. So-
Nikhil: So I can even do this?
kostadis: Yeah, you can do that as well.
Nikhil: But, uh, is there a chance that I can know what this work is before accepting the side quest?
kostadis: You... So just to be clear, a side quest is presented, you don't actually have to take it.
Nikhil: Which means I know the w- what the side quest is?
kostadis: Yes.
Nikhil: Okay. So what is the work that she has for us?
kostadis: You wanna go there first?
Nikhil: No, I just want to know what the work is. I don't wanna accept it.
kostadis: Yeah, I mean, sure you wanna go talk to her, is that what... Right? Correct. Yeah
kostadis: All right. Um, uh...
Nikhil: I think there's just a shrine of luck.
kostadis: Yes. Um, so she, you arrive at the shrine. Oh, no, I did not put you on the shrine of luck, sorry. Let's, uh, do that now
kostadis: Shrine of luck. The Shrine of Luck is over there. All right. You okay? Yeah. You're at the Shrine of Luck. All right. This small shrine is made of stones taken from nearby ruins. It is dedicated to Tymora, the god of luck and good fortune. Sister, the, the shrine is in the care of a scholarly acolyte named Sister Grail.
kostadis: Um, she sees you and smiles and says, "Well, the new heroes of Phandalin."
Nikhil: Thank you.
kostadis: I see that you did, you, you, you cleared out the Redbrands, and everybody is walking with a s- happier step in their, in their pockets
Nikhil: Okay. Now I need WhatsApp and if somebody's pleasing, it is people.
kostadis: Just like, okay, just that's fine.
kostadis: All right. Um-
kostadis: So she goes, "Since you did so mu- such a good turn for the Redbrands, I have, I may have a job for you."
Nikhil: Okay. How can I help you?
kostadis: Um, "My..." I- she looks at her, looks at you and says, "I need my... I was asked to pursue a rather delicate mission."
Nikhil: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Uh, "They wanted me to pursue a dangerous banshee, Agatha, to ask her, answer a question about a spell book."
kostadis: You wanna know what a banshee is, or you're just gonna go, "Mm-hmm"?
Nikhil: I, uh, I don't know. I, I was thinking it was
kostadis: similar to bandit, but I can see on the- No,
Nikhil: you can ask her.
kostadis: Okay. What is a banshee?
Nikhil: Uh, she goes, "A banshee is an undead creature."
kostadis: Oh, okay.
Nikhil: That's good. "
kostadis: Of considerable power." Mm. "And in fact, that's why I need your help, because I underestimated her anger when she attempt, when I attempted to approach the banshee.
kostadis: But I fled for my life, I have to admit it, and I barely recovered after several days. But I did notice that the banshee spoke wistfully about the beautiful gems and baubles she had in her life." Mm-hmm. "I need you to bring her a suitable gift, a jeweled silver comb, and persuade the banshee to tell us what she knows about the late's location of a s- spell book beco- belonging to a legendary name, mage named Bowgentle."
Nikhil: Does Veyra familiar with that name?
kostadis: Uh- Any
Nikhil: expression from that?
kostadis: Uh, does Veyra know about Bowgentle? Um, let's see. "Yes," she says. "She is? Yes." And she pulls out her notes and says, "Bowgentle. Yes, he's in my notes."
Nikhil: Mm-hmm. He's in my notes
kostadis: Do you know him? No,
Nikhil: no, no, I don't know him. He's legendary. Yeah, he,
kostadis: he- Oh, he's a legendary.
kostadis: Okay, okay. Na-
Nikhil: na- name did enter my notes
kostadis: Justin Which is a good sign
Nikhil: Okay. Yeah
kostadis: Means that he's, he's real. Do you look over her notebook?
Nikhil: No
kostadis: Okay. Um, she goes, "If you're willing to, if you're willing to perform that-"
Nikhil: She goes, "If you're willing to do, do that, I'm willing to give you three potions of healing as payment for your efforts."
kostadis: See. Okay, I don't want to negotiate with her. I'll just accept.
Nikhil: You'll accept?
kostadis: Yeah, I'll just accept as in, like, uh, I'm gonna tell her that, uh, "Okay, I'll help you in bringing an offering to the banshee.
kostadis: Um, but I would need some time to, uh, take care of a few other businesses, like-"
Nikhil: So, so you're telling her that, "I'm gonna take care of it, but not right now"?
kostadis: Yes.
Nikhil: She's like, "Well, the good news is the banshee isn't going anywhere."
kostadis: That's what I thought.
Nikhil: The bad news
kostadis: is we do really need that information, so don't take too much time.
Nikhil: Well, definitely not. I'll prioritize this right away after we finish.
kostadis: Some other high priority things. Yes,
Nikhil: after-
kostadis: It, it's a P0, but there are other, there, there... It's a P0, but a sev three.
Nikhil: It's a P0, but not
kostadis: everything's
Nikhil: P0. Yeah.
kostadis: All right. Let me just, uh-
Nikhil: Well, yeah. Okay, Nick. Uh, then, yeah, I wanna make a business call.
kostadis: What's the business call?
Nikhil: Business call to Halia.
kostadis: Ah, okay. So I just want you to know that this is, uh, this is, you know, how the Agatha's Lair is on the map. Right. You should go to the... If you go to the Roll20s tab, you should see it. Scroll up.
Nikhil: Uh-huh.
kostadis: Go up. Zoom out.
Nikhil: Yeah, zoom out.
kostadis: Agatha's married. Okay.
Nikhil: All right. Okay. Um, all right.
kostadis: So, uh, wait, so what Halia told me was she then invited, invited everyone to call on at the exchange about future prospects.
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: So, yeah. I'm gonna make the call or maybe, I don't know.
Nikhil: You're, you're gonna show up at the Miner's Exchange.
kostadis: Miner's Exchange, yes.
Nikhil: All right.
Nikhil: Do you see the lineage?
kostadis: Yes, yes, I'm going to, um, get my lineage exchange. Hold on. There. You should see it now. It's under the lineage of Cluster.
Nikhil: Okay. Mm-hmm. You see it? Yeah, I see it I see that.
kostadis: All right. The Miner's Exchange is a trading post where local miners have their valuable finds weighed, measured, and paid out. In the absence of any local authority, the m- Exchange also serves as unofficial records officers office, registering claims to various streams and excavations around the area.
kostadis: Mm-hmm. The Exchange is a great place to meet people who spend a lot of time in the country sounds- countryside surrounding Phandalin. There isn't any real gold rush in Phandalin, but enough wealth is hidden in the nearby streams and valleys to support a good number of independent prospectors. Um, Halia smiles at you and introduces herself as the guild master.
kostadis: Mm-hmm.
kostadis: Uh, some
kostadis: She, um, she sm- she sees you arrive and smiles. Why
Nikhil: are we smiling?
kostadis: Well, a little bird told me that the Redbrands are a thing of the past.
Nikhil: Okay, cool. Ah, yeah.
kostadis: Somebody, the, the Dendrars said that you were heroic in defeating them.
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: And they said, if I'm not, if I understood correctly, that you defeated the great leader who ran the place?
Nikhil: Well, there could have been a little bit of exaggeration, but you have the right information.
kostadis: Oh, that's so wonderful. So Glasstaff is dead?
Nikhil: Uh, no
kostadis: She stops smiling. She, she stops smiling. Uh,
kostadis: and did you kill all of the Redbrands?
Nikhil: I believe so. Do you think any of them are alive, Halia?
kostadis: Roll your insight.
kostadis: Investigation.
Nikhil: Oh, fuck. That's a four.
kostadis: All right. Roll your investigation. Or roll with advantage. Uh, sorry, you rolled a four. You, you have no idea what she's saying. She tr- she changes the topic. She goes, "But the Glasstaff is gone."
Nikhil: Wait, is she making the statement?
kostadis: Or- She's making the statement. "But Glasstaff is gone, and that is a good thing.
kostadis: And the Redbrand, whatever is left over, are leaderless, and that is a good thing, too." And then she pauses and says, "Do you, um..."
kostadis: Uh, did you by any chance find any correspondence?
kostadis: Hmm? Well, it, among his personal effects
Nikhil: Why do you care about
kostadis: it happening? But anyway, I'm thought she goes, "I, I am, I, I'm, I'm a local authority here. I would love to know if there was any deeper plots involved in the honor."
Nikhil: Wait, how is she a local authority?
kostadis: Miner's Exchange. She's running the Miner's Ex- She thinks of herself as a miner. Like, basically-
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah.
Nikhil: She's part of the Miner's Exchange, or
kostadis: is- She runs the Miner's Exchange
Nikhil: That's, that's like the government body of the-
kostadis: It's kind of a... It's not a government body, but it's the closest thing they have to a government.
Nikhil: Okay. She, she was, like, one of the elites in the village.
kostadis: Yes, yes.
Nikhil: Okay.
kostadis: Right.
Nikhil: Um,
kostadis: she goes, "I care about business."
kostadis: And I wanna know if business and trade will be disrupted. The Red
Nikhil: Brands were very disruptive
Nikhil: Well, let me assure you this, that your business and trade will not be disrupted anymore by the Redbrand.
kostadis: Ooh, that sounds very ominous. She pauses and says, "Would you be willing to part with any letters you found for a small fee, perhaps 100 gold pieces?" Stone Dark
kostadis: Halia
Nikhil: Yes
kostadis: Let me tell you this
kostadis: The information I want from the Tresendar banner Yes Is far, far more valuable than the
kostadis: hundred gold pieces you're offering. If there's anything else that you can offer that is of value to me, let me know, and we can talk about that
Nikhil: She smiles. "
kostadis: Hmm, you like to negotiate." I like to help "You like to help? I see." Uh
Nikhil: All right. All right, she ju- she leaves it at that.
kostadis: But- She goes- She was very suspicious when she was ... She knew that there was some correspondence that is strange, right? And she behaved earlier
Nikhil: that, you know, she just discovered that the other day was a bit weird.
kostadis: Yes.
kostadis: Resume might be worth investigating later.
Nikhil: Yeah. In- In
kostadis: private.
Nikhil: Yeah.
kostadis: All right, dude, it's been three hours.
Nikhil: Yes.
kostadis: I think we can call it a day.
Nikhil: Awesome.
kostadis: Did you have fun?
Nikhil: I did. Uh, kind of I'm really
kostadis: glad to see that you had fun with this